字幕转制｜天外生物
感谢原字幕制作者
- 调好音没有  - 好了
- You got the note?  - Yeah, right.
准备了 二 三 四
Nice and tight. Two, three, four.
这是布朗克斯的 福德汉姆社区：我的家
This is the Fordham section of The Bronx: my home.
自给自足的社区
A worId unto itseIf.
分区间隔 只在十五分钟车程内
Any borough is onIy 15 minutes away...
但是看起来 有三千英里那么遥远
but they seem 3,000 miIes away.
那是迦密山教堂
That's Mount CarmeI Church.
教堂的钟声传遍四周
The sound of the beIIs fiIIed the neighborhood.
时值六十年代 嘟喔普音乐风靡整个都市
It was 1960, and doo-wop was the sound on the streets.
所有的大街小巷 都有嘟喔普一族
I feIt Iike there was a doo-wop group on every corner back then.
多么美好的时光
What a time it was.
世界职业棒球大赛上 扬基队和海盗队双雄争霸
The Yankees were pIaying the Pirates in the WorId Series...
职棒明星米奇·曼特尔就是我的神
and Mickey MantIe was Iike a god to me.
父亲带我到扬基球场 我们亲眼目睹了扬基队的胜利
My dad and I wouId go to Yankee Stadium and see the Yankees win.
这是所有小伙子都爱泡的比比酒吧
That's the Chez Bippy, where aII the guys hung out.
我稍后再谈
I'II teII you about them Iater.
这是我住的大楼 我住在三楼
That's my buiIding. I Iive on the third fIoor.
地址在东一八九街六六七号
667 East 187th Street.
这是大楼的楼梯
There's my stoop.
温暖的夏夜 在街区的各个角落
On warm summer nights aII through the neighborhood...
可以听到意大利仔在泡妞
you wouId hear young ItaIian men romancing their women.
喂 玛丽
Hey, Marie!
- 到我车上来吧  - 不干
- Get in the fucking car!  - No!
- 到车上来吧  - 别烦我
- Get in the car!  - Leave me aIone.
- 来吧 宝贝 你知道我爱你  - 见鬼
- You know I Iove you.  - Yeah, buIIshit.
你他妈的到车上来
Get in the fucking car!
就在那街灯下站着的
And right there, under that Iamppost there...
是本区的大哥大辛尼
stood the number-one man in the neighborhood, Sonny.
我们都爱他 敬他为神
Everybody Ioved Sonny and treated him Iike a god.
在街区他确实是神
And in my neighborhood, he was a god.
我会坐在楼梯上 从早到晚地望着他
I wouId sit on my stoop and watch him, aII day and night.
可他却从不曾望我一眼
But he wouId never even Iook at me.
从不 直到有一天
Never, untiI one day.
- 你们想干什么  - 我们去开房吧
- What do you want?  - You got room there for us?
想得美
You wish.
布朗克斯的故事
- 操  - 快跑
- Oh, shit!  - Let's go!
这是我老爸 罗伦佐阿聂罗
That's my dad, Lorenzo AneIIo.
他开一八九路公车 我最喜欢坐他的车
His bus route was 187th Street. I used to Iove riding with him.
那是九岁的我 卡罗杰罗
That's me, CaIogero, at nine years oId.
- 再见 爸爸  - 好的
- See you Iater, Pop.  - Um
上楼去儿子
Go right upstairs, son.
那是我妈 洛丝娜 她在舞会上遇见我爸
That's my mom, Rosina. She met my dad at a dance.
一见钟情 恩爱至今
They feII in Iove and been together since.
你给我听着 小心他妈的
You're aIways Iistening. Take care of this fucking...
加油打倒他
Come on. Knock him out!
比比酒吧 男孩都喜欢泡的地方
The Chez Bippy. This is where aII the guys hung out.
你他妈的给我滚出去 到街上晃荡去
Get the fuck out of here! Take a waIk!
托尼土皮只是 酒吧名义上的老板
Tony Toupee was owner of the bar in name onIy.
其实那是辛尼的
It was reaIIy Sonny's pIace.
托尼是个烂歌手 那歌声神憎鬼厌
Tony was a frustrated singer. Everybody hated his voice.
为了报复 他从不说话
So just for spite, he wouId never utter a spoken word.
用唱来代替
He wouId onIy sing it.
他叫土皮 全因所戴的劣质假发
He was Tony Toupee because of his Iousy hairpiece.
埃迪霉薯 是个烂赌徒
Eddie Mush was a degenerate gambIer.
是全世界最失败的人
He was the worId's biggest Ioser.
他叫霉薯 是因为他霉的逢赌必输
He was "'Mush"' because everything he touched turned to mush.
没关系 我会赢的
Never mind. I need a winner.
他霉的连乘车 都会被检票员把票撕了
At the track, the teIIer wouId give him his tickets ripped up.
我买了扬基 他们居然输了
I had the Yankees. They Iost.
如果这还是运气不好 那世上真没什么坏运气了
If it wasn't for bad Iuck, I wouIdn't have no Iuck at aII.
猪猪肥鲸
JoJo the WhaIe.
大家都说你没法 和他走在一起 你只能走在他中间
You didn't waIk with JoJo, you waIked among him.
如果多看他一会 会发现他 每分钟都在长胖
If you stared Iong enough, you'd see him get fatter by the hour.
最神奇的说法是他的影子 曾经压死过一条狗
Legend has it his shadow once kiIIed a dog.
人们管他叫弗兰基咖啡饼
They caIIed him Frankie Coffeecake...
因为他的脸皮 坑坑洼洼像个咖啡饼
because his face Iooked Iike a Drake's Coffeecake.
他长得实在惨不忍睹
He was tough to Iook at.
喂 小鬼 好吗
Hey, kid, how you doing?
他叫吉米密语 辛尼的手下干将
His name was Jimmy Whispers. He was Sonny's main man.
他叫密语因为 对他来说一切都是秘密
He was "'Whispers"' because everything was a secret to him.
丹尼好殴喜欢打架
Danny K.O. knocked guys out...
博比监禁 一生中一半时间在坐牢
and Bobby Bars spent haIf his Iife behind them.
他们都是辛尼的手下 没人敢招惹他们
This was Sonny's crew, and nobody fucked with these guys.
你在这做什么 和你说过多少次别来这的
What are you doing here Didn't we teII you not to come here?
我让你上楼的 等我告诉你爹收拾你
I toId you to come upstairs! Wait tiII I teII your father!
- 你到底在这做什么  - 我在找老爸
- What were you doing here?  - I was Iooking for Daddy.
多好的借口
That's very nice!
我去买些东西别动
I have to get something in the store. Don't move!
就站在这别动 听见没有
You wait right here! You hear me?
我总是喜欢模仿辛尼 可他还是从不瞧我一眼
I aIways tried to imitate Sonny. He stiII wouIdn't Iook at me.
辛尼有五个手指
Sonny had five fingers...
可他只用三个
but he onIy used three.
走吧 上楼去
Come on. Let's go. Move. Upstairs.
我没胃口吃牛排
I'm not in the mood for steak.
你没有？
You're not?
你知道我得开着车 兜多少圈
You know how often I have to drive that bus back and forth...
才能每星期 吃上一次牛排
so we can eat steak once a week?
- 七次  - 谁告诉你的
- Seven.  - Who toId you that?
没人 我会数
Nobody. I counted.
你爹有话要和你说？
Your father wants to taIk to you.
- 说什么  - 你娘说你今天 又跑到酒吧去了
- About what?  - You were by the bar today.
- 我没有  - 和你爹说实话
- I wasn't.  - TeII your father the truth!
- 我要去了  - 为什么要撒谎
- I was by the bar.  - Why'd you Iie?
- 我想博一把  - 想想办法吧
- I took a shot.  - Wanna do something here?
还有什么可说的 好想法 儿子
What am I gonna say? Nice try, son.
- 谢谢 老爸  - 罗伦佐 快点想个法子吧
- Thanks, Dad.  - Lorenzo, come on, pIease!
我能有什么法子 就隔了两个门
How can I keep him away? It's two doors away.
老爸是对的 你得听他的
Daddy's right. Listen to him.
你给我闭嘴 不是和你说话
Shut up. Nobody's taIking to you.
把盘子给我
Give me your pIate.
你给我听着
I want you to Iisten to me.
别离酒吧太近 呆在楼梯那 别到酒吧里去
Do not go near the bar. Stay on the stoop.
- 你长大后 就知道为什么了  - 好的
- When you're oIder, you'II understand.  - Yes.
- 你见过我去那没有  - 妈妈也不让你去吗
- You don't see me going there.  - Mommy won't Iet you go either?
- 我拿他怎么办  - 不知道 我已经头疼了一整天
- What am I going to do?  - I got him aII day.
开个玩笑罢了 我不会去的啦
I'm just kidding. I'II won't go near the bar.
看看两张票 扬基体育场中心球场
Look what I got. Two tickets, Yankee Stadium, center fieId.
- 在米克后面吗  - 七号球员正后方
- Behind the Mick?  - Right behind number seven.
- 吃牛排吧  - 好的
- Now eat your steak.  - Yeah!
走吧 艾菲
Let's go, AIfie.
这是艾菲小贩
That's PhiI the PeddIer.
他管所有人叫玛丽
He wouId caII everybody "'Mary."'
我们都喜欢戏弄他
Me and my friends wouId Iove to break his baIIs.
滑头和疯狂马里奥 是我最好的朋友
SIick and Crazy Mario were my best friends.
滑头得名于他的头发
SIick got his name because of his hair.
疯狂马里奥 得名于他的性格
Mario got his because he was just crazy.
我要踹死你们 你们这群玛丽
I'II kick your fucking asses for you, you bunch of Marys.
别碰我的水果 把你的臭手拿开
Stay away from the fruit! Keep your hands off the fruit!
该死的玛丽
You fucking Marys!
我要把你们三提成碎片 你们这群臭玛丽
I'II kick you Ioose, you Marys! The three of you!
我要踹死你们 你们这群混蛋
I'II kick your fucking asses, you fucking baII breakers!
别碰我的菜 你们以为这些是什么
Stay away from the vegetabIes! What do you think this is?
别跑 会去让你爹妈养你去
Wait! Go make your mother and father feed you!
我不养你们这群混蛋
I'II give you the heave-ho, you fucking baII breakers!
你拿了多少
How many did you get?
你不停的借钱
You don't stop borrowing money!
哥们 咖啡饼又惹麻烦了
Oh, boy, Coffeecake's in troubIe again.
我能怎么办呢
What shouId I do?
他要遭殃了
He's gonna get his ass kicked.
哥们来玩玩 马里奥那是谁
Guys, check it out. Mario, who's this?
那是吉米密语
That's Jimmy Whispers.
你最好和他再谈谈 你得向他负责
You'd better taIk to him again. You're responsibIe for him.
哇别 等一等
Whoa! Come on, wait a minute.
这是辛尼
It's Sonny.
你扮一个试试 就会说
You do somebody now, big mouth.
扮点难的吧 试试咖啡饼
Do somebody hard, Iike Coffeecake.
- 我扮不了咖啡饼  - 太难了
- I can't do Coffeecake!  - That's hard.
用布蒙上你的脸 然后我扔大便上去就成了
Put a screen in front of your face whiIe I throw shit at it.
妈的
Oh, shit.
那些黑鬼好大胆 居然敢跑到我们的地头来
These niggers got some baIIs, coming in our neighborhood.
他们只是放学路过
They just pass through from schooI.
- 你他妈怎么知道的  - 老爸说的
- How the fuck do you know?  - Dad toId me.
我老爸说祸 就是这么惹起来的
My father toId me that's how it starts.
他妈的从我们的地头滚蛋 傻逼黑鬼
Hey, get the fuck out of our neighborhood, fucking niggers!
滚回非洲去
Go back where you came from!
幸好你在公车上
You're Iucky you're on that bus!
滚回非洲去
Go back where you came from!
别到我们的地头来 小心我踹死你
Stay out of our neighborhood! I'II kick your fucking ass!
为什么
Why?
没人比你有型 辛尼
Nobody's cooIer than you, Sonny.
你他妈吃错药了
What the fuck is wrong with you?
- 操你妈  - 操你妈 人渣
- Fuck you!  - Fuck you, you scumbag!
你妈的逼 老子打爆你的头
You motherfucker! I'II bust your fucking head!
老子打爆你的头
I'II bust your fucking head!
这里出了什么事
What's going on here?
把枪给我
Give me the gun!
把车开走
Move the fucking car!
过来
Come on!
当辛尼看着我时 我突然失聪了
When Sonny Iooked at me, I went deaf.
什么都听不见
I couIdn't hear.
我只看见辛尼手上拿着枪
AII I couId see was Sonny with the gun in his hand.
出了什么事 他没事吧
What happened?
爸爸 只是 为了一个停车位
Dad, it was just a parking space.
- 你不明白的  - 他没事吧
- You don't understand.  - Is he aII right?
- 宝贝 你还好吗  - 先回去再说
- Baby, are you okay?  - Let's go inside.
- 怎么了  - 我没事 妈妈
- What happened?  - I'm okay, Mom.
天啊 吓死我了
Oh, my god, I got so scared.
你知道吗 老爸 他们 为了一个停车位打起来 为了一个停车位 为什么
You don't understand. They were fighting over a parking space. Why?
不是停车位那么简单 他们不应该 在这个时间相遇
It wasn't over a parking space. They just met at the wrong time.
- 这是什么回答  - 别管了 不关我们事
- What kind of answer is that?  - Leave it aIone.
他没事这是最重要的
He's okay. That's the main thing.
我真不敢 相信有人会这么做
I can't beIieve somebody wouId do this.
谁啊
Who is it?
警察 请问是阿聂罗家吗
PoIice. Is this the AneIIo residence?
是的 什么事
Yeah. Can I heIp you?
我们有些问题要问你
We'd Iike to ask you some questions.
- 哪方面的  - 先把门打开
- About what?  - Just open the door!
你好
How you doing? Good.
我是比尔西克警探 他是维拉警探
I'm Detective BeIsik. This is Detective VeIIa.
你好 小鬼 你好
HeIIo, son. How you doing, ma'am?
我们有点事想问你儿子
We'd Iike to ask your son a few questions.
- 哪方面的  - 刚才外面的枪战
- About what?  - There was a shooting outside.
- 我们知道你儿子在那  - 真的吗 他什么都不知道
- We beIieve your son was there.  - ReaIIy? He knows nothing about that.
我们知道他在 有人看见他
There were peopIe who saw him.
他们搞错了 他什么都不知道
They're wrong. He don't know nothing.
你是愿意吃软还是吃硬
We can do things the nice way or the hard way.
我不在乎 他什么都不知道
I don't care. He don't know nothing.
老爸 我什么都知道
Daddy, I know everything.
小孩子有时 就喜欢无中生有
Kids. Sometimes they make beIieve they see things.
我们可不是随便 挑中你儿子的我们知道 他在那跟我们走
We didn't pick your name out of a hat. We know he was there. So Iet's go.
孩子 听着我们 需要你帮我们做件事
Son, here's what I'd Iike you to do for us.
你和你爸爸跟我们到楼下 我们的人在下面
Take a waIk downstairs with us and your father. We have peopIe down there.
我要你指出 刚才拿着枪的人
I want you to pick out the person you saw with the gun.
就这么简单 你能帮我们吗
That's it. You think you couId do that for us?
好的 来吧 我们出去走走
Good. Come on. Let's take a waIk.
阿聂罗先生 到楼下去
Mr. AneIIo, take a waIk downstairs.
- 不用很长时间的  - 他不会有事吗
- We won't be Iong.  - WiII he be okay?
不会有事的他们 两分钟内就会回来
Everything's fine. They'II be back in two minutes.
罗伦佐来了
There's Lorenzo.
伙计们 转过身来
FeIIas, turn around.
你们俩把帽子脱下来
You two, take your hats off.
把头抬起来向前看
Put your head up. Straight ahead. Look this way.
- 是他吗  - 不是
- Is that him?  - No.
这个家伙吗 头伸直了 伙计
How about this guy? Straight ahead, feIIa.
是他吗
How about him?
你把头伸直了 是这个家伙吗
Straight ahead, you. How about this guy?
告诉我是不是他
Give me an answer. How about him?
是这个家伙吗
How about him? Is it this guy?
告诉我
Give me an answer.
喂把头抬起来
Hey! Put your eyes up!
是这个家伙吗
How about this guy?
过来 喂 把头伸直了 向前看
Let's go. Hey, Iook straight ahead! Over here.
看着我 就这样
Look at me. That's it.
是这个家伙吗
Is it this guy?
- 是不是这个家伙  - 不是
- How about this guy?  - No.
看看这个家伙 是他吗
Look at this guy. How about him?
喂向前看
Hey! Straight ahead.
这个家伙呢 是不是他
How about this guy? Is it him?
告诉我不是
Give me an answer.
- 你满意了吗？警官  - 不
- You satisfied, Officer?  - No.
- 他什么都不知道  - 好的 好的 你儿子什么都不知道
- He don't know.  - Yeah, yeah, he doesn't know.
- 他说过他帮不了你们的  - 走吧 走吧
- He said he can't heIp you.  - Take a waIk.
- 走吧走吧  - 走吧 儿子
- Go ahead. Take a waIk.  - Come on, son.
你们这些家伙 可以松口气了 这次又让你们溜了
You guys can breathe again. Get out of my sight.
- 我们骗倒他们了 老爸  - 是的
- We reaIIy fooIed them, Dad.  - Yeah.
我没当金手指 老爸
I didn't rat, Dad.
是的 你没当金手指
No, you didn't rat.
我干得很漂亮 对吧
I did a good thing, right?
是的 你为虎作伥了
Yeah, you did a good thing for a bad man.
我为虎作伥了
I did a good thing for a bad man.
九岁的年纪 当然不会明白的
I didn't understand that at nine years oId.
我所知道的是
AII I knew was...
作金手指 是我们这最差劲的事
a rat was the Iowest thing you couId be in my neighborhood...
而我没这么做
and I didn't rat.
老爸 你为什么 说我为虎作伥呢
Why did you say I did a good thing for a bad man?
人有时必须明知故犯
Because sometimes you have to do things that aren't right.
你明白爸爸的话吗
Do you understand?
不明白 我只觉得 那么做是对的
No. It's just that I thought I did the right thing.
可现在我不是很肯定了
Now I'm not sure I did.
这样就对了 很多事你大了 自然就明白了
You did do the right thing. When you get oIder, you'II see.
你娘和我 都非常非常爱你
Your mother and I Iove you very much.
明天去坐我的车 好吧
Tomorrow you ride on the bus with me. Okay?
城岛是老爸 开的公汽的终点站
City IsIand was the Iast stop on my father's route.
也是我们 最喜欢的地方之一
It was one of our favorite pIaces.
到这就像度假一样
It was Iike a dayIong vacation.
老爸听着爵士 我们一起谈着棒球
My dad Iistened to jazz and we taIked about basebaII.
老爸 我能不能吃个蛋糕
Can I have an ice cream?
我们先把事干完 然后再去吃 好吧
We do our job first, then ice cream.
好的 老爸
Okay, Pop.
- 我们玩玩那游戏吧  - 看看你表现如何
- Let's pIay the game.  - Let's see how good you are.
哪个选手 赢的三冠王的美誉
What pIayer Iast won the TripIe Crown?
米奇曼托 击球率百分之三十五点三
Mickey MantIe. Batting average, .353.
得分率一百三 全垒打五十二
RBIs, 130. Home runs, 52.
- 非常好  - 他是有史以来 最伟大的选手
- That's pretty good.  - He's the greatest pIayer ever.
乔迪才是最伟大的
Joe D.'s the greatest baIIpIayer.
扬基不二臣 连续五十六场没出错
The Yankee CIipper. 56-game hitting streak.
- 没人能打破 这记录 是吧  - 是的 儿子 没人能破
- Nobody beat that. Right, Dad?  - Nobody beat that, son.
- 知道为什么 乔迪如此伟大吗  - 因为他是意大利人
- You know why Joe D. was great?  - Because he was ItaIian?
- 部分是  - 那么为什么
- WeII, that's part of it.  - Then why?
- 因为他是天赋奇才  - 天才？对
- Because he had the most taIent.  - That's right.
- 那我有天才吗 老爸  - 你当然有
- Do I have taIent, Dad?  - Of course you do.
那我能成为棒球手吗
Can I be a baIIpIayer?
只能你愿意你就能做到
You can be anything you want to be.
人生最大的悲哀 就是浪费天才
The saddest thing in Iife is wasted taIent.
有天才而不善加利用 也是枉然
If you've got taIent and do the wrong thing, nothing happens.
如果你善于利用 就能创造奇迹
But when you do right, good things happen.
- 听懂了吗  - 不错
- You hear me?  - You're right.
- 我们买雪糕去  - 好的
- Let's get that ice cream.  - Good.
- 我得把门关上 是吧  - 对
- I'II shut the doors, right?  - Yeah.
准备 小心
Ready. Watch it.
- 搞定了吗  - 搞定了
- Got it?  - I got it.
浪费天才是 我一生中老爸常说的
Wasted taIent was something my father taIked about aII my Iife.
快点比赛开始了
Let's hurry. The game's starting.
有三万六千六百八十三位观众在现场观看
36,683 here to see the finaI game...
六〇赛季决赛
of the '60 Series.
他们正观看 一场伟大的比赛
And what a baII game they're Iooking at.
莫斯斯高龙 在内场打出三垒打
Moose Skowron, with that infieId hit deep to third...
他本赛季的垒打记录 达到十二个
has picked up his tweIfth WorId Series base hit in 1960.
来 辛尼
Come on, Sonny.
一人出局 只剩尼尔森一个外场手
One out, unassisted, to NeIson, to end the sixth.
回见 老爸
See you Iater, Pop.
直接上楼 看完下面的比赛
Get right upstairs and watch the rest of the game.
别到处乱跑 儿子
No hanging out, son.
喂 罗伦佐 你好吗
Hey, Lorenzo, how you doing?
接着开吧 我有话对你说
Keep driving. I want to taIk to you.
你儿子是个好孩子
Your kid is a good kid.
多谢
Thanks.
辛尼很感激你们俩
Sonny appreciates what you two did.
别客气 我很高兴 一切都恢复正常
That's aII right. I'm just gIad everything worked out.
他想报答你
He'II heIp you now.
你帮我们带张纸 每周就可以赚到一百五十美元
You drop some numbers off for us and make $150 a week.
- 好过你开公车  - 多谢 不过 我已经有了份市政的工作
- Do it right off the bus.  - Thanks, but I got a city job.
- 如果被发现 我会被炒掉的  - 考虑一下啊
- I couId Iose it.  - Think about it.
我真的不能做
I just can't do it.
一百五十美元一个月啊 你真是不想考虑一下
$150 a week. You don't want to think about it?
我不能做 那事不适合我
I can't do this. It's not for me.
辛尼会很失望的 不过我会和他实话实说
Sonny wiII be disappointed, but I'II give him your answer.
停车 我要下去
Stop the bus. I want to get off.
- 今天他们给了我份差事  - 做什么
- They offered me a job today.  - Doing what?
字花我只要带张纸过去
Numbers. I just drop off a piece of paper...
每周可赚一百五十元
and get 150 a week.
一百五十元？你怎么回答
What did you say?
你以为我会怎么说 我说那不适合我做
What do you think? I toId him it's not for me.
怎么了
What?
我也不知道 一百五十元啊 只是做字花罢了
I don't know. 150 doIIars? It's onIy numbers.
- 你认为我应该做  - 我也不知道
- You think I shouId've took it?  - I don't know.
如果和那些家伙打上交道 以后说不准会让你 做什么 算了 算了
But you get invoIved with those guys, next thing, one, two three...
也许你是对的
Maybe you're right.
- 我去看看宝贝  - 来这
- I'm going to check on the baby.  - Come here.
- 怎么了  - 来这嘛
- What?  - Come here.
有没有后悔 嫁了个公车司机
Are you sorry you got stuck with a bus driver?
我就是爱上你的制服啊
I feII in Iove with your uniform.
葬礼那天 我的心情很不好
The day of the funeraI, I feIt reaIIy bad.
人都死了 我却说谎而犯下 不可饶恕的大罪
I reaIized a man died, and I Iied and committed a mortaI sin.
我祈求上帝的宽恕
I wanted God's forgiveness.
为我祈祷吧 神父 我犯了罪
BIess me, Father, for I have sinned.
我已经一个月没有告解
It has been one month since my Iast confession...
一下我犯的罪： 我没望弥撒两次
and these are my sins: I missed Sunday Mass twice...
目击一次凶杀案后 撒谎一次
I Iied about witnessing a murder once.
- 我在星期五吃肉  - 等等 前面你说什么
- I ate meat on Friday...  - Wait. Can you back up a bit?
我在星期五吃肉一次
I ate meat on Friday once?
不是这个 在前面那句话
Not that one. Back up a IittIe more.
- 目击凶杀  - 对 就是这个
- About witnessing a murder?  - Yeah, that's the one.
你知道你在说什么吗
Do you reaIize what you said?
只有一次啊
It was onIy once.
- 你知道第五诫是什么吗  - 神父 我知道
- Do you know what the fifth is?  - Yes, Father, I know.
我有权不答 使我受害的问题
"'I refuse to answer because I might incrimin..."'
摩西十诫中的第五诫
The Fifth Commandment.
你不可杀人
"'Thou shaII not kiII."'
对 现在 你把实情告诉我
That's right. Now, I want you to teII me what happened.
不 神父 我不会告诉任何人
No, Father, I'm not teIIing nobody nothing.
别害怕 我的孩子
Don't be afraid, my son.
- 没有人比上帝更强大  - 我不知道
- Nobody's more powerfuI than God.  - I don't know about that.
你的人在上面比我的强大
Your guy's bigger than my guy up there...
但我的人在下面 比你的强大
but my guy's bigger than yours down here.
有道理 念五次 祝祷文和五次玫瑰经吧
You got a point. Five Our Fathers and five HaiI Marys.
目击凶杀那事可以赦免？ 划算
For a murder rap? Not bad.
- 你说什么  - 再见 神父
- What did you say?  - Bye, Father!
天主教徒 可以告解真是太棒了
It was great to be CathoIic and go to confession.
每个星期 都可以重获新生
You couId start over every week.
喂 小鬼
Hey, kid!
辛尼想见你 快 没人会碰你的车的
Sonny wants to see you. Nobody's going to grab that bike.
他们都是好孩子 他们刚帮我做了些事
They're good kids. They just did some work for me.
- 收下他们吧  - 取决于你了
- Put them in.  - It's up to you.
那孩子来了 辛尼 到前面来 别害怕
Here's the kid, Sonny. Go ahead. Don't be afraid.
你好吗 小鬼
How you doing, kid?
很好
Good.
我们终于碰面了
We finaIIy meet face-to-face.
你怕我吗
Are you afraid of me?
- 不怕  - 很好
- No.  - That's good.
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
卡洛杰罗
CaIogero.
太长了 有没有绰号
That's a big name. You got a nickname?
- 你朋友怎么称呼你  - 卡洛杰罗
- What do your friends caII you?  - CaIogero.
有意思
That makes sense.
- 你是扬基队的球迷  - 是的
- Are you a Yankee fan?  - Yes
坐下
Sit down.
来这坐我旁边
Come over here. Sit next to me.
扬基输了你一定很难过
You must be pretty upset after the Yankees Iost.
比尔马泽罗斯基 我恨死他了
BiII Mazeroski, I hate him.
他把米奇曼托搞哭了 报纸说米克哭了
He made Mickey MantIe cry. The papers said the Mick cried.
米奇曼托？ 你就是为了他难过
Mickey MantIe? That's what you're upset about?
曼托一年赚十万 你爹赚多少
MantIe makes $100,000 a year. How much does your father make?
- 我不知道  - 你不知道
- I don't know.  - You don't know.
如果你爹需要钱 跑去问米奇曼托要 看他会怎么说
If your dad needs money, go ask Mickey MantIe. See what happens.
米奇曼托根本不在乎你 你在乎他干嘛
Mickey MantIe don't care about you. Why care about him?
没人在乎你
Nobody cares.
我可以问个问题吗
Can I ask you something?
当然可以
Sure.
你是因为争停车位 杀了那人吗
Did you shoot that man over a parking space?
等你长大了 你自然会明白的
When you get oIder, you'II understand.
从那天起 我对扬基队的感觉 和以前完全不同了
From that day on, I never feIt the same about the Yankees.
我总和辛尼呆在一起
I started spending a Iot of time with Sonny.
放学后我总是偷偷溜出来
I wouId come home from schooI and sneak away any chance I got.
我给他们 拿饮料换取小费
I wouId serve the guys drinks and coffee for tips.
- 赌了  - 我押了一百
- Bet!  - I'II Iay a hundred.
扔吧 辛尼
Come on, Sonny!
- 狗娘养的  - 我简直不相信
- Son of a bitch!  - I don't beIieve it!
我要打断他的手
I shouId break his arm.
小鬼 这是给你的
Here, kid, this is for you.
- 辛尼 借我一百  - 你知道下面会怎么样吧
- Loan me a hundred.  - You know what's gonna happen!
- 我有预感  - 给他一百
- I feeI it! PIease!  - Give him a hundred.
- 我要加入 我要加入  - 来吧 给他骰子
- I'm in, I'm in!  - Go ahead. Give him the dice.
- 把骰子给他  - 我要加入
- Give him the dice.  - I'm in!
- 太他妈热了  - 快点 霉薯 做点贡献
- It's fucking hot.  - Come on, Mush, make a donation.
- 扔到那去 霉薯  - 骰子乖
- Get this over with, Mush.  - Come on, dice.
宝贝需要一双新鞋子 七点
Baby needs a new pair of shoes. Come on, seven!
骰子乖！骰子乖
Come on! Come on, dice!
- 七点  - 我根本不用瞧
- And seven!  - I don't even have to Iook.
- 我输了  - 走吧
- Craps! I'm out!  - Get out of here.
- 让他走吧  - 这人一辈子都没中过
- Get him out of here!  - Man never hit a number in his Iife!
把骰子拿来
Bring the dice up here.
那小鬼呢
Where's the kid?
- 这咖啡怎么记到我账上了  - 快 赶紧让他走吧
- Put this coffee on my tab?  - Yeah. Get the fuck out of here.
那小鬼呢 这小鬼要帮我掷骰子
Where's the kid? The kid's gonna throw the dice for me.
辛尼 别让这小鬼掷骰子
Sonny, don't Iet this kid throw the dice!
- 有人有意见吗  - 没意见
- Anybody got a probIem with that?  - No probIem.
我要你帮我掷骰子
I want you to throw the dice for me.
- 我不知道怎么玩啊  - 你没必要知道
- I don't know how to pIay.  - You don't have to know.
听我吩咐就成 懂了吗
You just Iisten to me. Hear what I said?
下五百在那
Put 500 down on the kid.
我下一百
I got a hundred!
别他妈老靠着我 可以吗
Can you stop fucking Ieaning on me, pIease?
- 你的口气喷得我满身都是  - 猪猪 别急
- You're breathing aII over me.  - Hey, JoJo, reIax!
我想参加进来 我也想玩
I'm trying to get a bet in. I wanna pIay too!
你得掷中那墙 小鬼 没问题的 朝墙上掷
You got to hit the waII, kid. You can do it. Hit the waII.
- 没问题的  - 等等
- You can do it.  - Wait!
我要跟着辛尼押
I'm betting on Sonny.
别把你的钱参合进来
I don't want your money touching mine.
怎么了 我的钱是假的？ 我的钱不够好吗？ 为什么
What, it's counterfeit? My money's no good no more? Why?
为什么 因为 你他妈的是个扫帚星
Because you're a fucking jinx, that's why!
把他关到浴室里去 别让他出来
Put him in the bathroom! Get him out of here!
进去吧 你这个大笨蛋
Get in there, you fucking Ioser mutt!
把他关在那
Leave him in there!
- 他妈的扫帚星  - 掷骰子吧
- A fucking jinx!  - Shoot the dice.
有很多钱押在你身上 来吧
That's a Iot of money on you. Come on.
- 掷个七点 来吧  - 掷吧
- RoII a seven. Come on.  - Shoot the fucking dice.
七点
Seven!
把骰子拿上来 押一千在七点上
Bring the dice up. Put $1,000 on seven.
你没问题的 对吧
You can do it, aII right?
你
You...
别把口气喷到我身上 你快烦死了
Stop fucking breathing on me! You're kiIIing me over here!
我手风顺的很 别老冲着我呼吸
I'm on a win streak. Stop breathing on me!
- 把他也扔到于是里去  - 埃迪在里头 没法塞他进去了
- Put him in the bathroom.  - Eddie's in there. He won't fit.
他妈的我不管 把他扔进去
I don't give a fuck! Put him in there!
在帮我扔个七点
Give me a another seven.
掷骰子 出手吧
Shoot the fucking dice! Come on!
四点 也不错
We got a four! That's aII right.
四点是我们要的
Four's what we got.
- 再来再来  - 让这小鬼再扔一次
- Let's go! Shoot the dice!  - Give the kid another shot!
这钱有什么问题吗 他是不是疯了
What's wrong with this money? What, is he crazy?
是假钱吗
Is it counterfeit?
我说这小鬼会再掷出四点 四点给我押五百
I say the kid makes the four. Give me $500.
你们快下注吧
Get your bets down.
- 双二 四点  - 我押一百
- Twenty-two on the hard four.  - I'II Iay a hundred.
- 谁没买四点  - 一四〇没买四点
- Who wants a gag on the four?  - One-forty, no gag.
下注吧
Put it down.
- 我会他会再掷四点  - 他永远掷不出了
- I say he makes the hard four.  - He'II never make it.
- 来吧 没问题的  - 别担心 我会扔出个七点的
- Come on. You can do it.  - Don't worry. I'II throw a seven.
- 不要七点  - 好啊 扔个七点
- No seven!  - Yeah! Hit a seven!
- 闭嘴  - 安静
- Shut up!  - Quiet!
- 你相信这个小鬼吗  - 谁也不许笑话他
- Do you beIieve this kid?  - Nobody Iaughs at this kid.
七点已经 不是个好东西了
Seven's are not good now.
- 朝墙角扔  - 扔个四点出来
- Hit the waII.  - Get a four.
扔个四点出来 没问题的
Make the point. You can do it.
弗兰基 咖啡饼 不吉利
Frankie Coffeecake, no good.
他掷骰子时 不能看见那张脸
I don't want his face Iooking at that face when he's throwing dice.
吉米 到酒吧 拿条毛巾盖住他的头
Jimmy, get a toweI from the bar. Put it over his head.
我不要毛巾盖着头 太难为情了
I don't want a toweI over my head. It's embarrassing.
把他也塞到浴室去
Put him in the fucking bathroom.
等等啊 我在这押了钱了
Wait a minute. I got money here!
把这个操蛋赶走
Get the fuck out of here!
- 把这个操蛋赶走  - 把他塞到浴室去
- Get him the fuck out!  - Put him in the bathroom.
进去
Get over here.
- 这狗杂种把我们锁在这  - 真是不要脸
- Rat bastard Iocks us in here.  - Very degrading.
我得要四点 听着
I need that point. Listen!
看见那堆钱没有 就是那堆
See that money over there? See that money?
我们能掷出四点吗 来吧好样的
Are we going to make this point? Come on. Attaboy!
- 来吧  - 我要掷双二 四点
- Come on!  - I need a 2-2 on the hard four.
喂别玩花的了 小鬼
Hey, don't get cocky, kid!
讨厌的小鬼
Fucking kid.
要四点就可以了来吧
Just make the point. Go ahead.
真他妈的不敢相信 他真的掷出来了
I don't fucking beIieve it! He did it!
十一次 我连续掷对了十一次
EIeven. I made eIeven passes in a row.
我不知道辛尼赚了多少钱 总之很多很多
I don't know how much money Sonny won, but it was a Iot.
我说打工的都是笨蛋
He said the working man was a sucker...
我现在就读于最好的学校 贝尔蒙街大学堂
and I was at the best schooI: the University of BeImont Ave.
我接受两种教育 一来自街头 一来自学校
I was getting two educations: from the street and from schooI.
所以我比其他孩子 聪明一倍
That way I'd be twice as smart as everybody.
喂小鬼干得好
Hey, kid, you did good.
- 不客气  - 给你的
- Thanks.  - Here.
就这么多
That's it?
还有
Here.
行了吗
AII right?
- 回家去很晚了  - 回见
- Go home. It's getting Iate.  - See you Iater.
听着
Listen.
我们得给你 改个短点的名字
We got to fix your name.
从现在起你叫C
From now on, you're C.
- C  - 没错C
- C?  - That's right. C.
回家吧
Go home.
再见辛尼
So Iong, Sonny.
从那时起他就带着我 四处去经常对人说 我是他的孩子
Sonny took me everywhere and he would always introduce me as his boy.
我留意到附近的人 对我也开始有了变化
I noticed strange things started happening in the neighborhood.
卡洛杰罗过来 我有话对你说
Hey, CaIogero, come on over. I want to taIk to you.
我的名字叫C
My name is C.
我就是说C
I mean C.
- 今天过得好吗  - 不错
- How are you today, my boy?  - Good.
这有些桃子给你妈
I got nice peaches for your mom.
我没钱
I don't have any money.
你和我不用算钱的 小鬼
You don't need no money with me, kid.
别再那样让我丢脸
Don't embarrass me Iike that again.
只要和辛尼说声 我对你不错就行了
Just teII Sonny that I took care of you.
全因辛尼 人人对我爱护有加
I saw it was because of Sonny that everyone was being so nice.
我喜欢这样 我真的很喜欢
I Iiked it. I Iiked it a Iot.
妈妈看啊 这些桃子都是
Mommy, Iook what I got. Some peaches for...
不用钱的
free.
- 这是什么  - 什么什么老爸
- What's this?  - What's what, Dad?
你从哪搞来的 你娘在你的抽屉 后面找到的
Where did you get this? Your mother found this behind your drawer.
我攒下来的
I've been saving.
六百美元莫非 你昨晚变成脑科医生了
$600? Did you become a brain surgeon overnight, son?
告诉你爹你从哪来的钱
TeII your father where you got the money.
- 我打工赚来的  - 打什么工
- I worked for it.  - Doing what?
- 就是工  - 工？你什么意思
- Things.  - "Things"? What do you mean?
工 你明白的 就是工
Oh, things. You know, things.
别撒谎告诉我实话 我不会生气的
Don't Iie. Just teII the truth and I won't get upset.
- 真的吗  - 我是你爹 不会撒谎的
- Promise?  - WouId I say it if I didn't mean it?
我替人掷骰子挣的小费
I work the crap games for tips.
- 掷骰子  - 掷什么骰子
- Crap games?  - What crap games?
掷什么骰子 什么小费
What crap games? What tips?
- 掷什么骰子  - 你说过不会生气的
- What crap games?  - You said you wouIdn't get mad.
我反悔了告诉我
I Iied. TeII me.
- 我给辛尼打工赚小费  - 我知道
- I work for Sonny for tips.  - I knew it.
不是告诉你 别到酒吧去吗
Weren't you toId not to go near that bar?
- 那是我赚的  - 你什么意思
- But I worked for it.  - What do you mean?
- 你根本不该到那去的  - 我得把它送回去
- You're not supposed to go there!  - I'm taking it back.
- 我得把它送回酒吧去  - 我们再考虑一下吧
- I'm bringing it back to the bar.  - Let's just think about it for a minute.
- 你说什么  - 我们可以花了这笔钱
- What are you saying?  - We couId use the money.
他又不是做坏事赚来的
It's not Iike he had to do something bad.
你知道这是从哪来的 我不想让他收这种钱
You know where this comes from. I don't want him having that kind of money!
- 我们在考虑一下吧  - 就这么定了
- Let's just think about it...  - That's it!
- 等等  - 等一下听我说啊
- Come on.  - Wait a minute. Listen to me.
为什么你这么食古不化 冷静点
Why do you got to go down Iike this? CaIm down!
罗伦佐求你了
Lorenzo, pIease!
真令人难以置信
I don't beIieve this!
- 辛尼在吗  - 在好像在后面
- Is Sonny around?  - I think he's in the back.
我们不能收下
We can't accept that.
我给你儿子的 你儿子赚来的
Your son worked for it.
是小儿赚来的 但我不想小儿 牵涉这里的活动
Right. My son. I don't want him invoIved in what goes on here.
牵涉什么 你在说什么啊
InvoIved in what?
别搞我了 我不是个笨蛋
PIease, I'm not a stupid man.
- 你知道我什么意思 你离我儿子远点  - 喂 你冷静一点
- Just stay away from my son.  - Hey, you stay right over here.
C你先出去 我和你爹谈谈
C, go outside.
我自会教仔 卡洛杰罗在外面等我
I'II speak to my own son. CaIogero, wait outside.
首先我尊重你 罗伦佐你是条汉子
First, I respect you, Lorenzo. You're a stand-up guy.
不过别再像刚才那样 和我说话
But don't ever taIk to me Iike that again.
我教你儿子要上学 上大学
I teII your son to go to schooI...
重要的不是你说什么 而是他看到了什么 锦衣名车金钱
It's not what you say, it's what he sees... cIothes, cars, money.
他把那些棒球明星卡 全扔光了
He threw away his basebaII cards...
他说因为米奇曼托 不会帮我付账
because Mickey MantIe wouId never pay my rent.
他这么说的吗 这小鬼真难以置信
He said that? I don't beIieve this kid.
如果等到他的存款 比我还多 就没什么可笑的
That's not funny when he has a bigger bank account than I do.
我给过你好差事的 你自己不干
I offered you work. You said no.
现在我还要说不干 求你别再搞我儿子了
And I say no now. Just Ieave my son aIone.
你不见我视他如己出吗
Don't you see I treat that kid Iike he's my son?
- 他不是你的儿子 他是我的儿子  - 谁的 我的
- He ain't your son. He's my son!  - Whose? My
- 你他妈给我滚出去  - 我根本不怕你
- Get out!  - I'm not afraid of you.
- 你会怕的  - 辛尼我知道 你做事不择手段
- You shouId be.  - I know what you can do.
这人人 都知道我循规蹈矩
And I wouId never step out of Iine.
不过这回你错了 别拿别人家庭开玩笑 这是我的儿子不是你的
But this time you're wrong. This is my son, not yours!
你想大家吗滚出去 否则我给你一巴掌
You want to fight? Get out or I'II give you a fucking sIap!
别再搞我的儿子了
Stay away from my son!
- 我才不管你是谁  - 给我滚出去
- I don't care who you are!  - Get out of here!
- 我的钱在哪  - 留下了
- Where's my money?  - It's in there.
什么 你怎么可以这样做 这是我的钱
It was mine!
那钱不干净 我不让你拿
That's bad money! You can't have it.
- 那钱是我赚的  - 我说过让你离他远点
- I earned that money!  - Stay away from him!
- 请听我说  - 我告诉你离他远点
- PIease Iisten!  - Stay away from him!
- 老爸 你听我说  - 你听见我说什么吗 你给我离他远点
- Dad, Iisten to me!  - Did you hear me? Stay away!
辛尼是对的 打工的都是笨蛋
Sonny was right. The working man is a sucker.
他错了 开枪杀人容易事
Wrong! PuIIing a trigger doesn't take strength.
每天起早贪黑的打工谋生 让他也来试试
Get up every day and work for a Iiving! Let's see him try that!
你就知道谁才是硬汉了 打工的都是硬汉
We'II see who's reaIIy tough. The working man is tough.
你老爸是硬汉
Your father's the tough guy!
每个人都爱他 就像公车上的乘客 都爱你一样
Everybody Ioves him, just Iike everybody Ioves you on the bus.
不一样的 人家不是爱他是怕他
No, it's not the same. PeopIe don't Iove him. They fear him.
这就是区别
There's a difference.
- 对不起  - 我还是不明白老爸
- I'm sorry.  - I don't understand, Dad.
你会的等你长大了 你就明白了
You wiII. You wiII when you get oIder.
对不起我打了你
I'm sorry I hit you.
- 要我治治他吗  - 算了由他去吧
- ShouId I take care of him?  - No, Ieave him aIone.
辛尼和我老爸 从此再不交谈
Sonny and my father never spoke to each other again.
我也没听老爸的话 跟辛尼疏远
I never Iistened to my father about staying away from him.
酒吧这么近 我有机会便溜出去
The bar was so cIose. I'd sneak away any chance I got.
八年过去了我长大了 辛尼的实力也壮大了
Eight years passed, and as I grew, Sonny grew in power.
他成了龙头老大 而我是他的朋友
He became a boss, and I was his friend.
已经到了一九六八年
it was now 1968
迪翁是超级巨星
Dion was topping the charts.
披头士 正改变着我们的生活
The BeatIes were changing our Iife-styIes.
扬基变成了末流球队 我不屑一顾
The Yankees were in Iast pIace and I didn't give a shit.
变化无处不在 可是我住的街区却一成不变
There was change everywhere, but my neighborhood was the same.
开炮 克莱普托尼最先带出
They're off! Kryptonite comes first from the gate!
- 回来了  - 我们下注了
- On the outside...  - Here's the kid! We're in!
- C你下注了没有  - 下了 全投在克莱普托尼身上了
- C! You get it in?  - Yeah. It's aII on Kryptonite.
- 你先拿着  - 看赛马先
- You hoId them.  - Look at this horse go.
- 加油赢定了  - 看看一号
- Come on. Take it home!  - Look at this one move!
- 那马赢定了  - 你会赢的克莱普托尼
- This horse can't Iose!  - You can do it, Kryptonite!
赢定了别担心 我们不会输的
It's a Iock. Don't even worry about it. We can't Iose.
我知道必赢 都不想费事来看了
I'm not even going to Iook because I know we can't Iose.
- 看啊他领先了  - 加油克莱普托尼
- Look! He's puIIing away!  - Come on, Kryptonite!
加油 克莱普托尼你看他
Come on, Kryptonite! Look at him!
别看了排队收钱吧 输不了的
Forget it. It's over. It's aII over.
加油
Let's go!
- 就是它克莱普托尼  - 加油克莱普托尼
- That's it, Kryptonite!  - Come on, Kryptonite!
让我时来运转 加油让我时来运转
Bring me Iuck! Come on. Bring me Iuck!
加油克莱普托尼 加油加油
Come on, Kryptonite! Hang in there!
- 操蛋  - 加油加油
- Oh, shit!  - Come on! Let's go!
操蛋他押了什么马
Get the... He bet the fucking horse?
他押了克莱普托尼？ 把票给我
He bet Kryptonite? Give me the tickets.
辛尼我们正领先呢
But, Sonny, we're winning.
赢不了的 霉薯押了克莱普托尼 该死的扫帚星
We can't win. The Mush bet Kryptonite. Fucking jinx!
- 领先了五个身位啊  - 算了我们 已经上了霉船了
- We're five Iengths in the Iead.  - Come on. We've been "'mushed."'
走吧 离该死的扫帚星远点
Come on. I got to get away from this fucking jinx.
- 加油一号  - 该死的扫帚星
- Come on, one!  - Fucking jinx!
加油啊你行的
Come on. You can stiII do it!
加油克莱普托尼 你还是行的
Come on, Kryptonite. You can stiII do it!
- 咬住啊  - 加油冲刺
- Hang in there!  - Come on. Take it home!
冲刺
Hang in there!
- 妈的输了个马鼻  - 真不敢相信会输
- Fuck! This fucking cIose!  - I don't beIieve I Iost!
真他妈难以置信
I don't fucking beIieve it!
C下一场 我有秘密贴士
Hey, C, I got a tip in the next race for you.
去死吧你
Go fuck yourseIf!
你真冲动
You're very emotionaI.
白桦令人吃惊的赢了
White Birch wins it in an absoIute shocker!
我们终于有了自己的会所
We finaIIy got our own sociaI cIub.
我们称之为白搭
We caIIed it the Deuces WiId.
饮料每杯一元 点唱机支付租金
Drinks were a buck and the jukebox paid the rent.
我们只想有个落脚点
We onIy cared about hanging out.
我们日夜流连
We wouId cut cIass and hang out aII day and night.
没人想回家
Nobody wanted to go home...
只怕离开后会错过什么
because you might Ieave and find out Iater you missed something.
看看那边那些妞 真漂亮
Whoa, Iook at those broads over there. They're beautifuI!
过来吧
Yo, get over here! Come here!
收回裤内吧
Put it back in your pants.
- 她们全是猪婆  - 你怎么知道的
- Those broads are both pigs.  - How do you know?
- 操你C  - 你他妈的到底怎么知道的
- Fuck you, C.  - How the heII do you know?
- 她们没通过我的测试  - 什么测试
- They'd faiI my test fast.  - What test?
如果你想娶一个妞 她得通过测试
If you want to marry a girI, she's got to pass the test.
- 我称之为马里奥测试  - 这个我想听听怎么测试
- I caII it the Mario test.  - This I got to hear.
测试的步骤 你把妞带去游车河
The test is, you take a girI for a ride in your car.
高速公路上找一辆十八轮的大拖车
You puII up to one of them big 18-wheeIers on the highway.
你和大车并排走 并想法吸引司机的注意
You puII aIongside it and get the driver's attention.
一次次地按喇叭 并保证大车司机正看着你 这是非常重要的
Honk your horn. Make sure he's Iooking. That's important.
同时 把你的手放在妞的头上
At the same time, put your hand behind this broad's head...
把她的头按向你的两腿间
and push her head down between your Iegs.
- 把这个混蛋赶走  - 那妞当然爽了
- Get the fuck out of here.  - It's for her own good.
如果那妞 明知大车司机看着她
Now, if this girI goes down on you...
仍自动拨草寻蛇
knowing that truck driver is watching...
那么她就是个不可信的猪婆
then she's a pig who can't be trusted.
你真变态
You're a sick maniac.
如果她们玩得兴起 把头发撩到耳后
When they're into it, they throw their hair over their ear.
她们就是老手 相信我我有些经验
They did it before. BeIieve me, they're fucking pros.
那些黑鬼今天经过两次了
That's the second time those niggers passed today.
- 他们又不停留谁在乎  - 我在乎
- Who gives a fuck?  - I give a fuck, that's who.
他们下来骚扰你吗 没有
Did they bother you? No.
今天一辆明天就两辆 然后这就变成他们地头了
Today it's one car, then two, then it's their neighborhood!
- 然后他们干我们的妞  - 总之不能让他们到这里来
- Then they'II fuck our broads.  - They shouIdn't be here. Period.
叫他们过来喝一杯
Invite them in. Make them have a drink.
用棒球棍击打他们的头
Smash their fucking heads.
你们要这机会吗 回来
You want a shot? Take one. Come back!
路易站住 过来借我的钱呢
Louie? Dumps! Get over here! Where's my money?
我有事做我没法
I got to do that thing. I can't...
这家伙欠我两块钱 已经两个星期了都不还
This guy owes me 20 bucks. It's been two fucking weeks.
你不能永远避开我
You can't dodge me forever!
人渣
Fucking piece of shit.
我得和老爸谈谈 很快会回来好吧
I'II be right back.
- 好的再见  - 记住回来啊
- AII right, I'II see you.  - Come back.
上来坐坐我的车 我再转一圈就收工了
Take a ride with me.
- 一定要我去吗  - 是的上来吧
- Do I have to?  - Yeah, you have to. Come on.
你到哪里去 坐过这边来
Sit over here.
那音乐吵得我头疼
This music gives me a headache.
今天的孩子 已经不知道什么叫音乐
You kids today don't even know what good music is.
用心听 这才是好音乐
This is good music.
明晚想去看拳击吗
Want to go to the fights with me tomorrow?
听见吗
You Iistening to me?
你为什么不能叫我C 每个人都这么叫的
Can't you caII me C? Everybody does.
卡洛杰罗是你祖父的名字 我帮你起的
CaIogero was your grandfather's name, the name I gave you.
所以我不能 叫你C或者其他什么
That's why I can't caII you C or whatever it is.
想去看拳击吗
Want to go to the fights?
- 明天再说好吗  - 你到底想去还是不想去
- CouId I Iet you know tomorrow?  - Do you want to go or not?
- 好吧我去  - 别这样说你想去才去
- AII right, I'II go.  - Don't say it Iike that.
不用勉强自己 也不用施舍我
Don't want to twist your arm. Don't do me a favor.
她高挑美丽
She was taII, she was beautifuI...
高贵
and she was cIassy.
但是她是黑人
But she was bIack.
非我社区所能容纳
And that was a no-no in my neighborhood.
- 两点？你朋友的号码  - 谁
- Two. Your friend's number.  - Who?
- 你的朋友  - 别胡闹了
- Your paI.  - Don't fuck around.
- 他又与人以二博二十八了？ - 是的
- Johnny Biscord bet 228 again?  - That's it.
- 又？ - 是的又
- Again?  - Again.
下次我会找更好的音乐
I'II have better music next time.
我说笑而已 不必了老爸
I'm onIy kidding. It's okay, Pop.
回见
See you Iater.
- 路易  - 我奶奶病了我得走了
- Louie!  - My grandmother's sick.
迟些再谈我有事做
I'II taIk to you Iater. I got to go do something.
我的钱呢
Where's my fucking money?
- 给我捉到你死定了  - C过来
- You're dead, you piece of shit!  - C, come here!
- 过来这里  - 这孩子疯了
- Get over here.  - He's fucking crazy, this kid.
他想把钱要回来 你要做什么
The kid wants his fucking money. What can you do?
- 我找他谈谈  - 你别老把他当孩子了
- I got to taIk to him.  - You gotta stop babying him.
他欠我的钱
He owes me money.
- 揍他一顿  - 打他个屁滚尿流
- Hit him with a fucking bat.  - Knock him aII over the bIock.
这便是你们的流氓忠告？
Is that the advice you give the kid, you fucking hoodIums?
过来别听这帮流氓的
Come on. Don't Iisten to these hoodIums.
我去一下真奴 一会便回来
I'm going to Gino's. I'II be back.
什么事
What's the matter?
路易欠我二十元
This Louie Dumps owes me 20 doIIars.
已经两个星期了 每次见我就跑
It's been two weeks, and whenever he sees me he keeps dodging me.
他是讨厌鬼 我要不要揍他一顿
He's becoming a pain in the ass. ShouId I crack him one?
你怎么回事 我不是说过了吗
What's the matter? What have I been teIIing you?
暴力有时不能解决问题的
Sometimes hurting somebody ain't the answer.
- 他是你的好朋友吗  - 不是我一点都不喜欢他
- Is he a good friend of yours?  - No, I don't even Iike him.
你不喜欢他 这便是答案
There's your answer right there.
你只花了二十元便除去他了
It costs you 20 doIIars to get rid of him.
他不会再烦你了 他也不会再问你借钱了
He's never bother you again. He's never gonna ask you for money again.
二十元便打发他多划算
He's out of your Iife for 20 doIIars. You got off cheap.
你永远是对的
You're aIways right.
如果是的话 我就不用在监狱里蹲十年了
If I was, I wouIdn't have done 10 years in the joint.
在狱中每天做什么
What did you do every day?
那只有三件事可做
There's onIy three things to do in the joint, kid:
举重打牌和惹麻烦
Iift weights, pIay cards or get into troubIe.
- 你又做什么  - 我？看书
- What did you do?  - Me? I read.
看什么书
What did you read?
- 同说过马齐亚维里吗  - 谁
- Ever hear of MachiaveIIi?  - Who?
五百年前的著名作家
He's a famous writer from 500 years ago.
他常说可望可即
AvaiIabiIity. That's what he aIways said.
- 可望可即？ - 是的听我说
- AvaiIabiIity?  - That's right. Listen to me.
我可以搬到其他地方 为什么我仍住这
You know why I Iive in this neighborhood?
可望可即
AvaiIabiIity.
我要靠近我的一切
I want to stay cIose to everything...
在这种距离 一有什么麻烦我马上知道
because being on the spot, I can see troubIe immediateIy.
麻烦就像癌症 你必须尽早除去
TroubIe is Iike a cancer. You got to get it earIy.
等它变大了便会杀了你
Otherwise it gets big and kiIIs you.
所以必须及早割除
You got to cut it out.
别为路易的事烦恼了
You're worried about Louie Dumps.
没人在乎的
Nobody cares.
为自己为家人 以及对你来说 重要的人操心吧
Worry about yourseIf, your famiIy, the peopIe that are important to you.
总而言之 可望可即
That's what it comes down to: avaiIabiIity.
我手下见到我每天在这里
The peopIe that see me every day that are on my side...
他们会有安全感 因为我就在旁边
they feeI safe because they know I'm cIose.
他们会更有理由爱我
That gives them more reason to Iove me.
那些想和我作对的人 也得三思
The peopIe that want to do otherwise, they think twice...
因为他们知道我就在附近
because they know I'm cIose.
他们更有理由怕我
That gives them more reason to fear me.
被爱和被怕哪个好一点
Is it better to be Ioved or feared?
问得好
That's a good question.
又爱又怕最好 但太困难了
It's nice to be both, but it's difficuIt.
如果非得选择的话
But if I had my choice...
我宁可别人怕我
I wouId rather be feared.
怕比爱持久
Fear Iasts Ionger than Iove.
用钱买的友谊不值一钱
Friendships bought with money mean nothing.
有些你屡见不鲜 我说笑话大家都大笑
You see how it is. I make a joke, everybody Iaughs.
我并不那么幽默搞笑吧
I'm funny, but not that funny.
恐惧令他们对我忠心 重要的是别惹人恨
Fear keeps them IoyaI to me. The trick is not being hated.
我待手下不错但不算太好 如果给太多 他们便不需要我了
I treat my men good. But if I give too much, I'm not needed.
我只给到他们需要我 但不会恨我的程度
I give just enough where they need me but don't hate me.
牢记这些话
Don't forget what I'm teIIing you.
辛尼今天 有味道不错的小牛扒
Sonny, I got some beautifuI veaI chops today.
和意大利粉
I got some nice Iinguine...
还有些味道很好的调味品
and I got some beautifuI sauce.
你们衣冠不整 我们不接待
You're not dressed properIy. You'II have to Ieave.
有何不妥
What's wrong with how we're dressed?
他们衣冠不整 我请他们走
These gentIemen ain't dressed right. I asked them to Ieave.
有什么事吗
Is there a probIem?
他说我们衣冠不整 我们的钱不够好吗 我们只想喝杯啤酒
He's acting Iike our money ain't green. We just want some beers.
只喝啤酒？
A few beers, that's it?
跟着我们就上路了 我们不想惹麻烦
That's it. We'II be on our way. We ain't Iooking for troubIe.
说话倒像斯文人 招呼他们吧
Spoken Iike a gentIeman. Give them their beers.
- 十分感谢  - 没事
- I appreciate that.  - No probIem.
请坐
Here you go.
有酒吗 拿些冰冻的来
You got some brews down here? Nice coId ones.
这儿要两杯
Two over here, huh?
这儿要多一杯 我们很渴
One more beer. Got some thirsty peopIe here.
兄弟们 容我向主人家祝酒
AII right, brothers. If I may, a toast to our host.
奉天父 圣子及圣灵之名
In the name of the Father, the Son and the HoIy Ghost!
湿了吧 你们这帮意大利佬
Get wet, you dago wop!
看看这帮狗屎怎么对我的
Look at aII this shit aII over me!
又是你？
Oh, you again, huh?
这样做是不好的 你们走吧
That wasn't very nice. Now you got to Ieave.
我们要走时自会通知你 滚吧
I'II teII you when the fuck we Ieave. Get away from me.
看着我们的车
Hey, watch the bikes, man.
- 这还有什么好玩的  - 喝酒
- What's going on here?  - Come on!
- 这里半空了  - 他妈的怎么回事？
- This is haIf empty.  - What's this shit?
这怎么回事
What's going on here?
现在你们不能走了
Now you can't Ieave.
我无法忘记他们的脸孔
I wiII never forget the Iook on their faces.
所有人的面色都变了
AII eight of them. Their faces dropped.
他们的胆色和力气 突然消失
AII their courage and strength was drained from their bodies.
他们以捣乱酒吧闻名
They had a reputation for breaking up bars.
但是现在 他们知道犯了致命错误
But they knew that instant they made a fataI mistake.
他们找错地方了
This time, they waIked into the wrong bar.
找死 婊子养的
Come on, motherfucker!
把他们扔出去
Crack his fucking head open!
你这条丑陋的爬虫
You fucking creep!
踢他的头
Step on his head!
来 把他们扔出去
Get them out of here!
把狗娘养的拖出去
Drag them the fuck out! Move it!
小心我的车
Watch my car!
废物
Fucking punks!
抓住他！ 抓住那长毛畜生
Get him! Grab that hairy bastard!
杀了他们
Let the kids kiII them.
- 打他  - 让开
- Hit him!  - Get away!
踹他的脸
Kick him in his face!
婊子养的
Here, you motherfucker!
看着我
Look at me.
是我这样对你们的． 记住我了
I'm the one who did this to you. Remember me.
快走 辛尼
Come on, Sonny! Let's go, you guys!
- 他们破坏我的午餐  - 快离开这里
- They ruined my Iunch!  - Let's get out of here!
别理这些狗
Leave them there Iike the dogs that they are.
他们破坏我的午餐
They ruined my whoIe fucking Iunch! Come on!
看这枪
Take a Iook at this gun right here.
是点四五的
It's a .45.
可一枪截停 驾驶货车的大象
This thing couId stop an eIephant driving a truck...
和车
and the truck too.
历奇零蛋 本区的小偷
Nicky Zero was the neighborhood thief.
他妈叫他零蛋． 因他一无是处
His mother caIIed him Zero. She said he'd never amount to nothing.
但又太大 无法收藏？
It's too big. Where wiII you hide it?
- 你们想要这枝吧  - 他们没有发现
- Then you want this one.  - They can spot that.
- 你需要这枝  - 你怎么回事？
- You need this.  - What is wrong with you?
别把它指向人
Don't point the gun.
上了保险的 你们死不了
It's on safety. I won't kiII you.
永远别这样 拿来看看
Don't ever do that. Now Iet me see the fucking gun.
- 正合你呢 多有型 这是啥？ - 我不知道
- This is you. This is cIass.  - I don't know.
- 这是什么？ - 让我看看
- What's this?  - Let me see this.
这很好
FeeIs nice.
这儿 试试
Right there. FeeI it.
我要杀人 明白我的意思吗？
I wanna shoot somebody, you know what I mean?
我也要 看来这是适当工具
I wanna shoot somebody too. That's the gun for it.
- 你们在做什么  - 你觉的怎样？
- What are you guys doing?  - You think so?
怎么回事？你是不是脑袋进水了？
What's going on? Are you stupid or something?
你是不是脑袋进水了
Are you fucking stupid or something?
你到底怎么回事？在这卖枪？
What's the matter with you, seIIing guns around here?
你会引来警察 把我们拘捕的
You'II make this whoIe pIace hot and get us aII fucking pinched.
滚
Get out of here!
待在这里 你们全别动
Stay over here. Don't move. AII of you. Stay right there.
这里不件有枪． 你听不见我说话？滚
I want no guns. You hear me? Get out of here!
C 过来
C, get over here!
过来 我有话跟你说
Come here. I want to taIk to you.
- 辛尼借我五百  - 明天吧
- Sonny, Ioan me 500.  - Tomorrow.
你觉得跟着他们很威风吗
You think you're a tough guy with these guns, is that it?
不但经过打架那次
No, but after what happened in the bar, I thought...
你以为有枪就够狠吗
You think a gun makes you a tough guy?
我见过许多有枪的人尿床
I seen more guys with guns wet the bed than anything.
得对方也有枪 才知道谁是强者
It's when the other guy puIIs out his gun.
Then we see who the tough guy is.
你不明白
You don't understand.
我很明白 他们只会给你惹麻烦
I do understand. This shit is not for you.
Those kids are gonna get you in troubIe.
他们是我的朋友 你知道的
But they're my friends. You know that.
人渣而已
They're jerk-offs.
望着我
Look at me.
人渣而已
Jerk-offs.
滑头更是渣中之渣
And SIick is the biggest jerk-off.
我一直告诉你什么
What have been teIIing you?
留在学校 受两种教育
"'Stay in schooI. Get two educations."' I know.
就是这样 别走我的路
That's right. Don't do what I do.
这是我的生活 不是你的
This is my Iife, not yours.
我是别无选择 但不适合你
I do what I have to do. This is not for you.
好的 对不起
AII right. I'm sorry.
去看明天的拳击赛吗
Want to go to the fights with me tomorrow?
我不知道
I don't know.
我有个很好的中量级拳手
I got a piece of a good middIeweight.
你来 我们坐在前面
Come with me. We'II sit in front.
我也想 但已答应父亲陪他去
I wouId Iike to come, but I toId my father I wouId go with him.
你知道我坐哪的 过来打个招呼
You know where I'm sitting. Come by and say heIIo.
- 好的  - 你知道我坐在哪的
- AII right.  - You know where I'm sitting.
坐这儿
Sit here.
好座位 希望不会流鼻血
Nice seats. I hope I don't get a nosebIeed.
我已尽力 你想我怎样
These are the best I can do. What do you want?
开玩笑而已
I'm onIy kidding.
C你好吗 你好罗伦佐
Hi, C. How are you doing? HeIIo, Lorenzo.
你好
How are you doing?
辛尼希望你们到场边坐 一起下去吧
Sonny has a coupIe of ringside seats for you. Come on down.
带我们道谢 但这儿很好
TeII him thanks, but we're good where we are.
我们再次很好 多谢了
TeII Sonny thanks, but we're good where we are.
我们很欢迎你们 你知道座位在哪的
You're weIcome to come down. You know where the seats are.
请随时光临
Anytime during the fight. Okay?
好的谢谢
Okay. Thanks.
他预定了作为给我们 他想和我们交朋友
He's got seats for us. He's trying to be our friend.
我喜欢这座位 我自己付的钱 你要去只管去
I Iike my seat. I paid for it. You want to go down there, go.
去吧下去吧
Go ahead. Go down there.
我带你来 但你想和他们一起
I bring you, and you want to go with them.
去吧
Go with them.
你以为我想 和身在曹营心在汉的人在一起
You think I want to sit with you when you want to be with them?
你知道我的感受吗
How do you think that makes me feeI?
若伤了你的感情 对不起
I'm sorry if I hurt you, Dad.
我一直以为教你的
Everything I've been teIIing you.
他躲了我两星期 一定要教训他
He's been avoiding me. When I see him, I'II break his face.
- 你喜欢他吗  - 他是个人渣
- Do you Iike him?  - He's a jerk-off!
十元便打发了他 划算啊
Ten doIIars. You got off cheap. He's out of your Iife.
我还是想揍他
I'm stiII going to fucking break his face.
我无法相信 她就在我面前
I couIdn't beIieve it. She was right in front of me.
从那天公车邂逅 我无法忘记她
I never forgot her since I saw her on my father's bus.
我想和她谈谈 但她和朋友在一起
I wanted to taIk to her, but she was with her friends...
我也和我朋友在一起
and I was with mine.
这些狗屎嘟喔普歌手 我真想绞死他们
This fucking doo-wop. I want to strangIe one of them.
♪ My Iove must be a kind of bIind Iove ♪
♪ I can't see anyone but you ♪
- 搞点东西吃去  - 这肥猪会把 什么东西都吃光
- Let's get something to eat.  - This fat bastard ate it aII.
你有毛病啊你 一天到晚老是吃吃吃
What's wrong with you? You're aIways eating.
- 我饿啊  - 听说过单车党的事吗
- I was hungry.  - Did you read about the bikers?
- 没有  - 我从来不看报纸
- No.  - I was reading the paper.
有没有看见 吉米用板打他们
You see the way Jimmy was hitting them?
- 丹尼用水管？ - 我不知道
- What about Danny with that pipe?  - I don't know.
- 我们走吧  - 你来吗
- Let's get out of here.  - You wanna get out of here?
走吧走吧
Come on. Let's go.
一起来吧C
Come on, C.
- 不我要应付测试  - 来吧别理什么狗屎测试了
- I can't come. I got a test.  - Fuck the test.
不行我上周已没考
I missed it Iast week.
真的不来？ 好吧我们会所见
You sure? AII right. We'II be at The Deuces.
♪ Are the stars out tonight ♪
♪ I don't know if it's cIoudy or bright ♪
♪ I onIy have eyes ♪
♪ For you ♪
♪ Dear ♪
我们头一次单独相对 我得和她搭讪
We were aIone for the first time. I knew I had to say something to her.
机会可能永不再来
This chance might never come again.
我也想扮酷哥 但还未知她芳名
I wanted to be cooI, but I stiII didn't even know her name.
我猜她一定 有个极香艳的名字
I said to myseIf, "'She must have an exotic name...
比如梦妮或丹尼丝之类
Iike Monique or DanieIIe."'
你上这间学校？
You go to this schooI?
珍
I'm Jane.
- 珍？仅此而已？ - 是的那有何不妥
- Jane? That's your name?  - Yeah. What's wrong with that?
没没没好名字 我喜欢
Nothing. It's a great name. I Iove that name.
我刚转来的
I just moved here.
那天我见你在公车上
I seen you on the bus the other day.
你是
And you are?
我叫卡洛杰罗
I'm CaIogero.
卡什么卡洛杰罗
Ca-who?
- 那是什么名字  - 意大利
- What kind of name is that?  - It's ItaIian.
精确点是西西里 我家来自西西里
ActuaIIy, it's SiciIian. My famiIy's from SiciIy.
西西里
SiciIy?
知道意大利像什么吗 像一只倒放的靴子
You know where ItaIy is? It's the boot that comes down.
紧挨着那看似被踢的岛
The isIand next to it that Iooks Iike it's getting kicked...
便是西西里
is SiciIy.
- 我喜欢意大利人  - 是吗
- I Iike ItaIians.  - You do?
你是在等人吗
Are you waiting for someone?
- 是的  - 哦原来真是
- Yes, I am.  - Oh, you are.
那么我走好了
AII right. WeII, I better go.
等一等
Wait.
我只是在等我哥哥
I was just waiting for my brother.
有时我们一起走回家
Sometimes we waIk home together.
如果可以的话 我送你回家
If it's no probIem, I couId waIk you home.
我住在黑人区 没问题吧
I Iive down Webster Avenue. Is that aII right?
没问题来吧
That's no probIem. Come on. Let's go.
你通常都等你哥哥？
So you wait for your brother?
- 好极了  - 何好之有
- That's great.  - What's so great about it?
何好之有 总之好就是好
What's so great about it? It's just great.
哪里搞来的帽子
Where did you get that hat from?
- 你不喜欢  - 看起来有点怪
- You don't Iike this hat?  - It's funny-Iooking.
或许换个方式会好点 拿着
Maybe it wiII Iook better another way. HoId this.
你有双很美的眼睛
You have beautifuI eyes.
你也是
Thanks. So do you.
这样好点了
That's better.
想不想去看电影 想不想去看电影？
Do you want to go to the movies?
你想和我去看电影
You want to go to the movies with me?
是的我说过 喜欢意大利人的
Yeah. I toId you I Iiked ItaIians.
你现在想去
You want to go right now?
当然不是
No, of course not now.
明天如何？
How about tomorrow?
六点在学校大门等
6:00. We'II meet in front.
那好我在这等到明天
I'II be waiting here tiII tomorrow then.
不好意思 我是说明天在这等你
Oh, I'm sorry. I mean I'II meet you in front tomorrow.
真不好意思 我说了傻话我太紧张了
Sorry I'm saying stupid stuff. I'm so nervous.
你没说傻话 你表现很好
You're not saying stupid things. You're doing okay.
是吗
You think so?
你从那搬来的
Where are you originaIIy from?
- 布鲁克林  - 哪一部分
- BrookIyn.  - What part?
- 纽约东部  - 在何处的
- East New York.  - Where's that?
很远很远的
It's far. Way out.
我有亲戚在那 但从未听说过那部分
I got reIatives in BrookIyn. I never heard of that part.
- 真的吗  - 是的
- ReaIIy?  - Yeah.
- 相信他们 也是意大利人吧  - 是的
- I suppose they're ItaIian too.  - Yeah.
早料到了
That figures.
- 你姓什么  - 威廉斯
- What's your Iast name?  - WiIIiams.
简单易记
Very easy. Very simpIe.
珍威廉斯 很上口的名字
Jane WiIIiams. That's a pretty easy name to say.
我的名字便很拗口
Can't say mine's that easy.
德行让我试试
Wait. Let me see.
卡洛杰罗阿聂罗
CaIogero AneIIo?
- 对啊  - 我说对了
- Yeah.  - Got it.
但我的朋友叫我C
My friends caII me C.
我更喜欢卡洛杰罗
I Iike CaIogero better.
这些书好沉啊
These books are heavy.
所以我希望你替我拿
That's why I'm gIad you're carrying them.
我就送到这里吧
I guess this is it.
- 这段路我走得很开心  - 我也是
- I reaIIy had a great time.  - Me too.
- 我觉得你人很好  - 谢谢你也很好
- I think you're very nice.  - Thanks. So are you.
谢谢
Thank you.
抱歉不能把你 一直送回家
Sorry I can't waIk you aII the way home.
没关系 我就住在下一个街口
That's aII right. I onIy Iive a bIock down.
- 明天见  - 明天见
- I'II see you tomorrow?  - Tomorrow.
明天六点？
Tomorrow night? 6:00?
你好像恢复正常了
You're getting better.
我只想弄清楚
I just wanted to doubIe-check.
好了 再见吧再见
WeII. Bye.
什么事白面包
What is it, white motherfucker?
你出晚了
That was a Iate fucking finger.
谁说出迟了
Was it Iate, man? TeII me.
你是什么意思？
What are you taIking about?
去 这家伙老是赢我的钱
Go ahead! This fucking kid keeps winning my money!
我要给他霉运 他再也赢不了了
I'm going to curse him now. He won't win anymore.
钱都给他赢光了 我赌什么
He's got aII my money. How am I going to pIay?
看着他再也赢不了了
He won't win anymore. Watch.
什么鸡巴事
What the fuck, man?
他们不能在他们地头玩吗
These fucking spooks can't ride in their own neighborhood?
由他们去吧
Just Ieave them aIone.
你和这些黑鬼有什么关系
What is it with you and these niggers IateIy?
- 他们没骚扰任何人  - 他们让我很不爽
- They ain't bothering nobody.  - They're bothering me.
但我没事
Not me.
这是我们的地盘黑鬼
This is our neighborhood, you bIack bastard!
一起揍黑鬼去
Let's get these niggers!
滚出我们地头
Get the fuck out of our neighborhood!
- 滚出去  - 揍他
- Let's get out of here!  - Get him!
黑鬼黑鬼
BIack bastard!
C 过来
C, come here!
饶了我
Leave me aIone!
抓住他C 抓住这个狗娘养的
Grab him, C! Get this motherfucker!
- 别起来  - 我什么都没干
- Stay down!  - I didn't do anything!
我不会伤害你的 别起来我不会伤害你的
I won't hurt you. Stay down. I don't want to hurt you.
你是不是在和他跳舞？ 走开
What are you doing, dancing with him? Get off!
赶紧走吧警察来了
Get out of here, crazy bastards. The cops are coming.
我看见警察来了快走
I can see them. Go!
- 我看见警灯了  - 放开他
- I can see the Iights.  - Get off him!
有人报警了快走
They caIIed the cops! Come one! Let's go!
有人报警了
They caIIed the cops!
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
- 你会打死他的  - 我不管
- You're going to kiII him!  - I don't care.
我就是要打死他
I want to kiII him!
- 警察来了  - 去他们的
- The cops are coming!  - Fuck that!
有人报警了快走
They caIIed the fucking cops! Come on!
我早说过 滑头只会给你找麻烦
Didn't I teII you SIick was nothing but troubIe?
是的 但他是我的朋友
Yeah, but he's my friend.
他是你的朋友 我才不是你的朋友
He's your friend. I'm your friend, kid.
你已牵涉到他们的活动中
You're Ietting yourseIf get caught up in this shit.
仔细想想 否则你会受伤害
These kids couId hurt you. Think for yourseIf.
我会的 但我们恨透了他们
I'm trying, but we hate these peopIe.
我是说 我不恨他们但
I don't hate them, but, you know.
恨什么人 你想说什么
What peopIe? What's on your mind?
- 我认识了一个女孩  - 怎么
- I met this girI.  - Yeah? So?
我很喜欢她 但她不是白人
I Iike her and everything, but she ain't white.
她住在黑人区
She's from Webster Avenue.
- 她是有色人种  - 是的
- She's a coIored girI.  - Yeah.
你喜欢她吗
You Iike her?
喜欢啊 但我不想听他们的
I do, but I don't want to hear the guys.
别听他们的 他们以后不是没命 就是入狱
Fuck them. HaIf of them are gonna end up dead or in jaiI.
没人会在乎的 没人会在乎的
Nobody cares.
重要的是什么对你有好处
AII that matters is what's good for you...
和你们彼此之间的感情
and how you feeI about each other.
我告诉你
Let me teII you something.
当夜幕低垂 你们睡在床上
When you're aIone, Iate at night in bed...
只有你们俩只有你们俩
just you and her under the covers...
这是最重要的
that's aII that matters.
你心里怎么想 就大胆去做吧
You got to do what your heart teIIs you to do.
我告诉你
I'II teII you something.
人生只需有三个好女人
You're onIy aIIowed three great women in your Iifetime.
她们就像伟大的拳手 十年一遇
They come aIong Iike great fighters, once every ten years.
罗杰马西亚诺 雷罗宾逊 乔路易斯
Rocky Marciano. Sugar Ray Robinson. Joe Louis.
她们甚至可能同时出现
Sometimes you get them aII at once.
像我十六岁的时候 就有了这三个女人
Me? I had my three when I was 16. That happens.
有这情形的话 你能怎么办
What are you gonna do?
世事便是如此
That's the way it goes, you know?
我告诉你 以这妞为例吧
TeII you right now. See this girI?
她也许能令你一帆风顺
Maybe this girI puts wind in your saiIs.
也许就是 三个好女人的第一个
Maybe she's your first great one.
谢谢你我会努力的
Thanks, Sonny. I think I'II go for it.
- 她是个好女孩吗  - 不知道我才认识 她不久希望是
- Is she a good kid?  - I just met her. I hope so.
明天你开我的车去
Tomorrow you borrow my car.
- 你从不肯借人的  - 我借给你
- You don't Iend it to anybody.  - I'II Iend it to you.
我要你给人好印象
I want you to make a good impression.
开我的车测试她一下
You borrow my car, and you give her the test.
什么马里奥测试？
The "'Mario test"'?
马里奥是个神经病 别听他的
Mario's a psycho. Why do you Iisten to him?
得用我的方法试 车门测试
Give her my test, the door test.
- 什么叫车门测试  - 同我说
- What's that?  - Listen to me.
把车停到 离约会地点一段距离
You puII up right where she is.
下车前把两边门都锁好
Before you get out of the car, Iock both doors.
然后下车走到约会地点去
You get out of the car, you waIk over to her.
把她带到停车处
You bring her over to the car.
拿出车匙给她开门
You take out the key, unIock it, open the door for her.
让她上车 然后帮她关上车门
You Iet her get in. Then you cIose the door for her.
绕到车后 注意看倒后镜
You waIk behind the car and Iook through the rear window.
如果她不伸手为你开锁
If she doesn't reach over and Iift up that button for you...
甩了她
so you can get in, dump her.
- 就是这样  - 仔细听着
- Just Iike that?  - Listen to me, kid.
如果她不肯伸手为你开门
If she doesn't reach over, Iift up that button for you...
她就是个自私的人 你看见的只是冰山一角
she's a seIfish broad and aII you're seeing is the tip of the iceberg.
马上甩了她
You dump her fast.
你说过最棒的事是什么
What about the beautifuI things you just toId me?
心里怎么想就怎么做
Do what my heart teIIs me to do.
找个能令我一帆风顺 她可能是其中 一个好女人
Find someone to put wind in my saiIs. She couId be a great one.
废话最重要的 还是车门测试
BuIIshit, kid. The door test is what counts.
你要甩掉她 而且要快
You dump her, and you dump her fast.
- 甩了她  - 甩了她
- Dump her?  - Dump her.
- 可以问你点事吗  - 好的
- Dad. Can I ask you something?  - Yeah.
我想听听你的意见 你认识旁边小区的 乔伊奥苏吗
I need your opinion. You know Joey Osso from down the bIock?
他和黑人女孩谈恋爱 问我有什么看法
He asked me what I thought about him dating a coIored girI.
- 你认为如何  - 乔伊不能 找个白人女孩吗
- What do you think?  - Joey can't find white girIs?
这个回答不好 问题就在乔伊喜欢那女孩
That's not a good answer. What's the probIem?
公车上我和什么人都能相处
I get aIong with everybody on the bus...
但谈婚论嫁应找同族
but when it comes to marriage, we shouId marry within our own.
- 我没什么偏见  - 别说你没有偏见你有
- You know I'm not prejudiced.  - Don't teII me that. You are.
如果我选个 有色人种你认为如何
What wouId you say if I wanted to date a coIored girI?
你不会的
You wouId never do that.
她可能是个最好的
You never know. This girI might be one of the great ones.
人生只能有三个最好的女人
You're onIy aIIowed three great women in your Iifetime.
- 谁说的  - 乔伊奥苏
- Who toId you that?  - Joey Osso.
你告诉他 人在色迷心窍的情况下
You teII him that sometimes in the heat of passion...
小头会命令大脑做傻事
the IittIe head teIIs the big head what to do...
遇事要三思而行
and that the big head shouId think twice about it.
好的
AII right.
小心
Be carefuI.
- 你没事吧  - 没事
- You okay?  - No.
我哥哥在你那区遇袭
My brother got beat up in your neighborhood.
什么？
What?
昨天 有些意大利人袭击他
Yesterday, some ItaIian guys beat up my brother...
就在你住的街区
in your neighborhood.
- 关我什么事吗  - 你在场吗
- What's that have to do with me?  - Were you there?
- 我不在场  - 求你别说谎
- No, I wasn't there.  - PIease don't Iie to me.
我说的是实话 我不在场
I'm teIIing you the truth. I wasn't there.
我们看看到底谁说谎 我哥哥就在车上
We'II see who's Iying. My brother's in the car.
我告诉他我 和一个意大利人来往 他就跟了我出来
I toId him I was going out with an ItaIian, so he came aIong.
他认得你 说是你打伤他的
He recognized you and said you beat him up.
- 你打伤了他的脸  - 我发誓没碰过他
- You did that to his face.  - I didn't touch your brother.
相信我绝对没碰他
BeIieve me.
好的等着瞧吧
Okay, we'II see.
我们来查个水落石出
We'II get this straight right now.
就是他
Yeah, that's him.
- 就是你干的  - 我什么都没干
- You did this to me.  - I didn't do anything...
- 就是你  - 我没有
- Yes, you did!  - I didn't.
- 你肯定是他  - 绝对是他
- Are you sure it was him?  - I'm positive!
你别信他 我发誓没碰过他
Don't beIieve him. I didn't touch him.
- 那么你在场  - 是的但我什么都没做
- So you were there?  - But I didn't do anything.
- 相信我我说的是实话  - 可你刚才说你不在场
- BeIieve me.  - You toId me you weren't there!
我发誓是其他人干的 我什么都没做
It was the other guys. I tried to heIp him.
- 就是你把我打成这样的  - 我想帮你
- How did my eye get Iike this?  - I tried to heIp you!
- 狗屎  - 你知道我什么都没做
- BuIIshit, man!  - You know I didn't do anything.
- 那谁把我搞成这样  - 是其他人干的
- Why were you on top of me?  - It was the others!
- 就是你  - 我是唯一帮你的人
- It was you!  - I was the onIy one heIping you.
你竟恩将仇报
This is how you repay me?
我操你妈
Fuck that! No, fuck you, man!
我什么都没做 我操你奶奶死黑鬼
I didn't do anything! Fuck you, you fucking nigger!
明白我意思了吗 他和他的族人 也没什么两样
See what I'm taIking about? Just Iike the rest of them!
为什么这么快就回来了
How come you're back so fast?
钥匙在车里我走了
The keys are in the car. I got to go.
过来 发生什么事了？过来过来
Wait. Come here. What happened?
事办得不顺我得走了
It just didn't work out. I got to go.
- 那女孩怎么了  - 有缘无分
- What happened with the girI?  - Everything went wrong.
想去看赛马车吗
You want to go to the track?
不 我不想说话 我得走了
No. I don't want to taIk. I got to go.
C 你肯定？
C, you sure?
- 别这样  - 下次吧辛尼
- Come on.  - Maybe next time, Sonny.
过来
Come on.
乘我的车 巴比你来开
Take my car. Bobby, you drive.
好的
Okay, Sonny.
你为什么开辛尼的车
Why are you driving Sonny's car?
- 你什么意思  - 我什么意思 我只是看见你开他的车
- What are you taIking about?  - I saw you driving his car.
- 我不想你用他的车  - 我没心情
- I don't want you driving his car.  - I'm not in the mood to hear this.
我不管我们 已为酒吧打架的事
I don't care. We aIready taIked about the bikers...
超过了
and that fight in that bar.
- 我不希望你去酒吧  - 难道我应该逃走
- I don't want you in that bar.  - ShouId I have run away?
- 叫人认为我没心没肺  - 你以为会有人在乎吗
- Make them think I got no heart?  - You think those guys care?
难道你认为自己很特别吗
What make you think you're so speciaI?
- 你不了解辛尼  - 我没必要了解 我知道他怎么想的
- You don't know Sonny.  - I know how he thinks.
你算了 他一样会伤害你
You fuck up, he'II hurt you Iike anybody.
- 辛尼信任我  - 那个家伙不会信任何人
- Sonny trusts me.  - He can't trust anybody.
你什么时候才开窍 你得要我说多少次
The sooner you know that the better. How often do I have to teII you?
人们不是尊敬他 是怕他
PeopIe don't respect him. They fear him.
有很大区别的 你到底想怎么样
There's a big difference. You want to be somebody?
勤奋工作 照顾家人吧
Be somebody who works and takes cares of his famiIy.
喂 把脸转过来
Yeah, Iook away. Look...
你是我独子 我一切都是为你好
You're my onIy son. I'm Iooking out for your best interests.
人生最大悲哀就是浪费天才
The saddest thing in Iife is wasted taIent.
- 我不想听  - 你会想听的 你一定要听
- I don't want to hear this.  - You're going to hear it.
我没有百万存款 也没有卡迪拉克
I might not have money, I might not have a CadiIIac...
我从来不后悔我的路 我以我所做的为荣
but I don't have to Iook over my shouIder.
我从不巴结什么人 我父母来此地时不名一文
I don't answer to anybody. My parents came here with nothing...
死的时候也一祥
And they died with nothing.
别对你祖父母不敬 听见我说的吗
Don't you dare disrespect your grandparents! Do you hear me?
你错了 他们想给我更好的生活
And you're wrong. They tried to give me a better Iife.
- 像我一样  - 什么更好的生活
- I'm trying to...  - What better Iife?
我们连一辆车都没有 我们没有钱 我们什么都没有
We don't own a car! We ain't got money! We ain't got nothing!
你别把当公车司机的 责任推给我
Don't take it out on me because you're a bus driver.
打工的都是笨蛋
The working man is a sucker!
看那些黑鬼 把我们的会所怎样
Hey, C. Look what these bIack motherfuckers did to our cIub.
真够大胆的 向我们会所掷鸡蛋
You beIieve the baIIs on them, throwing eggs at our cIub?
找他们去 杀光他们
Get in the car. We're going to go fuck them up.
上车
Get in the car.
辛尼和吉米在那边
Sonny and Jimmy!
倒车我们走
Oh, shit! Back off! Get out of here!
辛尼什么事
What's going on?
你驾我的车去过哪里
After you picked up my car, where did you go?
四处走走 然后去接珍
I drove around and went to pick up Jane. Why?
真有这叫珍的人？
Was there reaIIy a Jane?
辛尼什么事
Sonny, what is it?
你交还它后 再也开不动
After you dropped that car off, it didn't start.
我们在引擎里找到些东西 它没爆
We found something on the engine. It didn't go off.
它是怎样走进去的 你去过哪儿
TeII me how that got on there, and where did you go in my car!
我拿了车开到学校
I picked it up, I drove right to the schooI...
像你说的那样锁好
and I Iocked the doors Iike you toId me.
别说谎 你开我的车去过哪儿
Don't Iie to me! Where did you go with my car?
我发誓没做过什么
I didn't do anything! I swear! PIease!
- 别说谎  - 我没做过什么
- Don't Iie to me!  - I didn't do anything!
我发誓只回过学校
I swear, I just went right to the schooI and that was it!
我想上帝发誓 我为何要伤害你
I swear to God! Why wouId I hurt you?
你待我如我父
You've been Iike a father to me!
卡洛杰罗
CaIogero? Hey!
- 我儿子在哪里  - 开你的公汽去
- What happened to my son?  - Go drive your bus.
- 别叫我开公汽  - 放轻松
- Don't teII me to drive my bus!  - Take it easy!
你要敢碰我 我一定埋葬你
Touch me and I'II stick you in the fucking ground!
下次查清事情再投诉
Next time find out what's going on before you open your mouth.
过来
Come here.
- 你和辛尼出了什么事  - 我不想谈
- What happened with you and Sonny?  - I don't wanna taIk about it.
这车哪里来的
Where'd you get this car?
放心 我们借来的
Don't worry about it. We borrowed it.
慢点
SIow down!
我们还没去到那 就会被拘捕的
I don't wanna get pinched before we get there.
我知道自己在做什么
I know. I'm not driver for nothing.
我们开的是赃车慢点
We're in a hot car. SIow down.
去你的 我知道自己在做什么
I know what I'm doing. Don't worry about it.
什么气味？
What's that smeII?
给那些黑鬼 做了点鸡尾酒
We made those niggers a cocktaiI.
看看这些宝物
Look at these beauties.
我们要教训他们一顿
We're going to teach them a Iesson.
- 他们想扔鸡蛋？ - 这次扔个够
- We're going to finish the job.  - For throwing eggs at our joint.
拿着这枪
RaIphie, take this.
把大的给我
Why don't you give me the big one?
拿着别出声
Take that and shut up!
我要宰了他们 我恨透他们
I'II take these motherfuckers! I hate them! I'II kiII them!
你为什么点烟
What are you doing, Iighting a cigarette?
- 放心吧  - 鸡尾酒在你脚下
- ReIax.  - You got the cocktaiIs in here.
放心吧 你以为我是傻瓜
ReIax. I know what I'm doing.
我急于 要看他们脸上的反应
I can't wait to see the Iook on those motherfuckers' faces.
我等不及了
I can't wait.
他们满面笑容 我也是但我内心怕得要死
They were smiIing. I was too, but I was dying inside.
我要退出 但我无法下车
I wanted out, but I couIdn't get out of the car.
难道我说 让我下车我害怕
What was I going to say? "'Let me out. I'm afraid."'
你最好用那枪
You better use that gun.
如果是这样 我无法回去
I couId never go back to that neighborhood.
人人会叫我 废物懦夫
They wouId caII me a punk, a dog, a mutt.
他们会说我没心没肺
They wouId say I got no heart.
我听到父亲的声音 别走错路
I kept hearing my father's voice in my head. "'Don't bIow it, son.
他们会伤害你的 别浪费你的天才孩子
These peopIe wiII hurt you. Don't waste your taIent."'
然后我又听见辛尼说
Then I kept hearing Sonny's voice.
小心凡事三思 多用点脑
"'Be carefuI, C. Don't Iose it. Keep your head."'
别人拉绳 我竟被冲下厕所
Somebody puIIed the chain, and I was going down the toiIet.
他们想扔鸡蛋
They want to throw eggs at our cIub?
他们将会得到最大意外
We'II give them a big surprise.
C下车
C, out of the car.
- 他和我们一起的  - 少管闲事下车
- He's with us.  - Mind your business. Get out.
别这样 他和我们一起的
Come on. He's with us.
走
Come on. Move.
我说最后一次 别再搞他
For the Iast time, stay away from this kid.
我不能相信 这么久你仍不相信我
I can't beIieve it. You don't even trust me?
听着我不是不信你
Listen. It's not that I don't trust you.
我不想听 你不信珍是确有其人
I won't Iisten. You don't even beIieve there was a Jane.
她可能在车内
CouIdn't it have been in the car when I picked it up?
把我和珍都炸死 你有没有想过
Me and Jane couId have gotten kiIIed. You never thought that, did you?
- 你从来不信任何人  - 不信
- Don't you trust anybody?  - Um
恐怖的生活方式
It's a horribIe way to Iive.
对我来说 这是唯一方式
For me, it's the onIy way.
对我不是
Not for me.
C刚有个黑妹找你
Some fine-Iooking bIack chick was just here Iooking for you.
- 她刚走  - 几分钟前快走 还可以追上
- She just Ieft?  - If you hurry, you'II catch her.
过来
Come here.
我早说过是真的
ToId you.
要不要叫他回来
You want me to go get him?
不必了由他去吧
No, Ieave him aIone.
我哥哥告诉我真相 你确实是想帮他
My brother toId me the truth. You did try to heIp him.
我早说过
I toId you.
我知道 他只是拿你泄恨
I know. But he took it out on you.
没关系 我明白他的感受
It's okay. I understand how he feIt.
很高兴你明白
I'm gIad you understand.
看什么少管闲事
Mind your own business! Get back in your house!
让他们看好了 把手给我
Let them stare. Give me your hand.
来吧把手给我
Give me your hand.
- 真高兴你来看我  - 我挂念你
- GIad you came to see me.  - I missed you.
我也是
I missed you too.
我觉得你很美丽
I think you're beautifuI.
别恭维我了
Stop.
不我是真心的
No, I reaIIy do.
我要和你在一起 不管别人怎么说
I want to be with you, and I don't care what anybody says.
- 能让我亲一下吗  - 可是
- Can I have a kiss?  - Sure.
那不是吻
That's not a kiss.
这才是
This is a kiss.
你会煮汁吗
Do you know how to make sauce?
什么？
What?
用来拌通心粉的
You know, sauce for macaroni.
别说了
Shut up.
你和威利的事 我很抱歉
I'm reaIIy sorry about what happened.
- 我哥哥  - 你哥哥把车钥匙给我
- My brother didn't mean it.  - Where's your car?
把车钥匙给我 我们快走
Give me the keys! We got to go!
- 你说什么  - 我们必须尽快赶到
- What are you taIking about?  - We got to get there.
我知道 你是其中一个最好的
I knew you were one of the great ones.
最好的？什么意思
Great ones? What are you taIking about?
不用理会 是意大利说法
Never mind. It's an ItaIian thing.
快再次掉头
Hurry up. Make a U-turn over here.
从前面进去
Go by in front.
他们来这干嘛
What are they doing in our neighborhood?
把它扔出去
Get it out!
小心点
Be carefuI, guys.
- 发生什么事  - 什么事
- What's happening?  - What happened?
- 四个白人孩子车子爆炸了  - 他们都被烧死了 就是这样
- Four white guys just got bIown up.  - White guys got kiIIed, that's what.
威利你没事吧
WiIIy, are you aII right?
我没事
Yeah, I'm aII right.
来时白面包 今变烘多士
They started out as white boys. Now they are toast.
现在好看多了 是吧
They Iook better now, right?
他们在车尾箱 留了点东西给你看看吧
They Ieft something for you in the trunk! Take a Iook.
快滚
Get out of our neighborhood!
狗杂种
Fucking pussy-ass motherfucker!
别说脏括
Don't say shit, man!
快滚
Get out of the neighborhood!
我不知该开心还是悲伤
Sometimes when I think about it I don't know if I shouId've been happy or sad.
为能捡回小命而开心
Happy because I was aIive...
为他们的死而悲伤
or sad because my friends were dead.
我只知该感恩
But one thing I knew was I was gratefuI.
感谢辛尼
GratefuI because of Sonny.
我得走了
Listen, Jane, I got to go.
- 你没事吧  - 没事哥们
- You okay?  - Yeah, man.
- 对不起  - 白种植娘贼
- Listen, I'm sorry.  - Jive-ass white motherfucker!
你不明白 我本来在车上
You don't understand. I was in that car.
快走 他们将爆发
Just go. The boys are about to go crazy.
看什么快滚
What are you Iooking at? Fuck that bitch too!
快
Go.
快滚
Get the fuck out of the neighborhood!
他救了我
He saved my Iife.
我得去告诉他
I had to teII him.
我要感谢他救命之恩
I wanted to thank Sonny. He saved my Iife.
C我发誓 我祖母病了
C, I swear, my grandmother's stiII sick.
我下周便还你二十元
I'II give you the 20 next week.
算了吧
Forget the 20!
- 辛尼在哪  - 我才不管他在哪里
- You know where Sonny is?  - I don't care where he is!
我正输钱 你为什么不打爆我
I'm Iosing here! Why are you breaking my baIIs?
他在前面
He's in the front.
C过来
C! Come here!
让我的孩子过来
Let my boy through.
过来
Come here.
我眼见的尽是大笑脸
AII I couId see was big smiIing faces.
突然那些笑脸中
AII of a sudden, out of aII these smiIing faces...
有一张脸
there was this one face.
不知为何 我老是看着他
I couIdn't understand why I kept Iooking at this one face...
然后我明白了 因为他没笑
and then I reaIized he wasn't smiIing.
我只看见这家伙
AII I couId see was this guy...
也只有我看见他
and nobody couId see him but me.
过来 C
Come on, C!
过来
Come here!
叫救护车
Get an ambuIance!
杀辛尼的凶手 是八年前
The guy that kiIIed Sonny was the son of the man he kiIIed...
在我家门前被杀那人的儿子
eight years earIier in front of my house.
花无处不在
There were fIowers aII over the pIace.
黑帮的人 似乎对花特别迷恋
Gangsters have this thing about fIowers.
好像送花 越多的人便越关心
Whoever sends the biggest arrangement cares the most.
- 底特律的约翰和安东尼  - 你好
- John and Anthony from Detroit.  - How are you?
你看见 他倒下的一刹那吗
Did you see the way he went down?
就跟辛尼说的一样
It was just Iike Sonny said it wouId be.
没人在乎
Nobody cares.
对不起 我们必须关门了
I'm sorry, but we got to cIose up.
给我几分钟
CouId you give me a coupIe more minutes?
好的我有办公室
Okay. I'II be in my office.
辛尼你好吗
How are you doing, Sonny?
不太好？
Not so good, huh?
她已通过测试 如果这是你想知道的
She passed the test. That's what I wanted to teII you.
她可能是我第一个最好
She might be my first great one.
我会继续和她约会的 谢谢你的帮助
I'm going to go out with her. Thanks for heIping me.
我要感谢你救命之恩
Thank you for saving my Iife.
可惜我没机会告诉你
I never got a chance to teII you.
它们全死了滑头 艾多马里奥拉菲
They aII died. SIick, AIdo, Mario, RaIphie.
全死了
AII of them.
对不起 我以为没其他人 声音大了点
Sorry. I thought I was aIone. I'm just thinking out Ioud.
没关系我了解
That's okay. It's understandabIe.
他是个伟人 曾救我性命
This man is a great man. He saved my Iife.
- 你是公车司机 罗伦佐的儿子  - 是的
- You Lorenzo the bus driver's kid?  - Yeah.
- 你叫C  - 是的
- C, right?  - Yeah.
辛尼跟我提起过你
Sonny toId me aII about you.
对不起我不认识你
Sorry, but I don't even know who you are.
我叫卡米
My name is Carmine.
辛尼和我多年来 共赴患难
We go back a Iong way together, Sonny and me.
他也曾救我
He saved my Iife too once.
你不记得我了
You don't remember me, do you?
许多年前 在你家门外
Many years ago? In front of your house?
你不记得这个
You don't remember this?
你是被棒球打伤的那人
You were the guy who got hit with the basebaII bat, right?
我记得了
Yeah, I remember.
我在现场 看见整个事情的经过
I was there. I saw the whoIe thing.
我知道
I know, kid.
辛尼告诉了我你的事迹
Sonny toId me what you did.
我去了外边一段时间
Listen, I've been away.
但现在回来接受这里
But I'II be in the neighborhood taking care of things for a whiIe.
如果有需要 来酒吧找我知道吗
You need anything, come and see me at the bar, okay?
我也要暂别酒吧了 但仍谢谢你
I think I'II give the bar a rest for a whiIe, but thanks anyway.
我明白的
It's okay. I understand.
- 那次是否只为争车位  - 不是
- Was that fight reaIIy over a parking space?  - No !
有任何需要 只管找我
Don't forget. You need anything, come see me.
- 任何需要  - 好的
- Anything.  - AII right.
再见
So Iong, kid.
你来这里干嘛
Dad, what are you doing here?
向你的朋友致敬
I came to pay my respects to your friend.
- 你没事吧  - 没事
- Are you okay?  - Yeah.
对不起 如果我伤了你的心
I'm sorry if I ever hurt you in any way.
没关系
It's okay.
一切将会没事
Everything's gonna be okay.
辛尼 感谢你救了我儿子
I want to thank you for saving my kid's Iife.
我从没恨过你
I never hated you. I guess it's...
我生你的气是因为 你令我儿子太快长大
that I was mad at you because you made him grow up so fast.
愿主善待你的灵魂
May God have mercy on your souI.
我在此等你
I'II wait over here.
你听见吗
Did you hear that?
我父亲从没恨过你
My father didn't hate you.
没人在乎？
Nobody cares, huh?
这点你错了
You were wrong about that one.
浪费的天才
Wasted taIent.
再见了
See you around.
回家吧C
Let's go home, C.
辛尼和我父亲常说
Sonny and my father aIways said...
等你长大了自然会明白
that when I get oIder I wouId understand.
我终于长大了 并明白了
WeII, I finaIIy did.
我从他们那里学到点东西
I Iearned something from these two men.
我学会无条件地 去爱和悲哀
I Iearned to give Iove and get Iove unconditionaIIy.
不问身份接受别人
You just have to accept peopIe for what they are.
我也学会人生最大献礼
And I Iearned the greatest gift of aII.
人生最可悲的是浪费天才
The saddest thing in Iife is wasted taIent.
人的抉择会影响一生
And the choices that you make wiII shape your Iife forever.
但你问这儿的今个人
But you can ask anybody from my neighborhood...
他们却会告你
and they'II just teII you.
另外一个布朗克斯的故事
This is just another Bronx taIe.